<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Jared Morgan (jaredmorgs) ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Technical Writer. Open Source Contributor. Co-host of the BlahCade Podcast. ]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net</link><image><url>/images/covers/pinball.jpg</url><title>Jared Morgan (jaredmorgs) </title><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 22:35:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Google Yelp, or how Google Local Guides just became more relevant]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I was sent an email yesterday outlining changes to the Yelp Communities program.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/Yelp_Communities_Dead.png" alt="Yelp Communities Dead.png" width="400px">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Communities program will be discontinued outside of the US.
That means that the Yelp Community Managers outside of the US no longer exist.
But more importantly, it means diminished recognition for the voluntary work you do for the ecosystem.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_the_yelp_that_was">1. The Yelp That Was</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A nice perk with Yelp was that you were invited to free hospitality events, and it made you feel a bit special. And this is important.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The thing with products like Yelp is that as a user, you are providing free content for their product. You write reviews and populate their ecosystem with information. Basically, user adoption and participation drive the success of the platform.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I often couldn&#8217;t go to the events because they were on in the evening and they didn&#8217;t fit into my family life. But that didn&#8217;t matter. The fact they were offered was the important thing.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_local_guides_as_a_disruptor">2. Local Guides as a Disruptor</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Enter <a href="https://www.google.com/local/guides/">Google Local Guides</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The program lets users plug into the Google Maps app, and contribute photos, reviews and confirm info about businesses and public venues. It&#8217;s basically Google Yelp.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The reason why I&#8217;ve begun to prefer Local Guides over Yelp is the seamless integration. If you navigate to a restaurant, and you begin taking photos of your food, you get a push notification suggesting you might like to update the business with the photo.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Local Guides is heavily gamified, in that you have a Level system and <a href="https://www.google.com/local/guides/benefits/index.html">get points</a> for five different content types:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Uploading photos</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Sharing reviews</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Adding new places</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fixing information</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Answering questions</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Each week you get a summary of how users have been consuming your content, and it is kind of staggering the reach your photos and reviews have.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_timeliness_is_key">3. Timeliness is Key</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Once you get your ranking up above Level 2, your "trust" level also rises. This is kind of the same as Yelp and it&#8217;s "Elite" program.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Because you are trusted more as a Google content creator, when you contribute a change to a business your changes get published quicker. And if you submit a new business listing, it gets approved much faster.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Recently I added a listing for a new business over in Newmarket, called KoKobana Superfood Cafe.</p>
</div>
<iframe src="https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d3541.0411386550322!2d153.0064174158907!3d-27.436828621876366!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x6b915767476ed5dd%3A0xbf8398cb7b0e271f!2sKoKobana+Superfood+Cafe!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sau!4v1478642546539" width="600" height="450" frameborder="0" style="border:0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On Google, my submission was available about 12hrs after I filled in the mobile form within maps. On Yelp, it took nearly a week for the listing o be approved. And this was with me as an Yelp Elite member.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This user experience was the final straw for me as a Yelp contributor. Why would I take the time to add a listing when it takes nearly a week to publish the thing? I can&#8217;t begin interacting with the listing like adding photos or updating details I may have got wrong during creation. It&#8217;s just plain frustrating.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_devils_advocate">4. Devils Advocate</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Of course, as a Google Local Guides you are basically a data surveyor. You add metadata about things Google values in products they own. They give you a cookie.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And it is probably fair to say that every contribution you make contributes to the metdata Google knows about you, and your dining and entertainment preferences. Probably more, in fact.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But I was just awareded 100GB of Drive storage for a year for reaching <strong>Level 4</strong> status. A reward that I can use daily, and fits into my family and time situation.
Google already knows everything about me anyway, so what burgers I like doesn&#8217;t seem like too much of an intrusion.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_summary">5. Summary</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Rewarding and recognising your content creators with even something small but tangible is a sure-fire way of keeping them loyal to your brand.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Take away incentives to contribute for your users, and you risk collapsing the framework that makes your service successful.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I bet I can level up to <strong>Level 5</strong> when I&#8217;m over in Europe. ;)</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/11/09/Google-Yelp-or-how-Google-Local-Guides-just-became-more-relevant.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/11/09/Google-Yelp-or-how-Google-Local-Guides-just-became-more-relevant.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Writing]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Users]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Apps]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[UBank Has NFC About Correct User Feedback]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;ve got a Google Nexus 6p which has all the things a current-gen handset should have. NFC is standard as it was on my Nexus 5 two years earlier, and the operating system is Android 7.1.1 (currently in Beta).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;ve wanted to try out contactless payments through my phone for a while now, and noticed that UBank offered this function through their app.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>What I discovered when trying to set this feature up made me question the ability of UBank to understand a typical user of their banking app for anything other than transferring money around.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_the_problem">1. The Problem</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The information shown when the app was unable to set up Mobile Payments was too technical for the audience. The real issue is that the information was just plain wrong.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/UBank_NFC_Nope.png" alt="UBank NFC Nope.png" width="400px">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>When I loaded the <code>Mobile Payments</code> menu in the app, I saw a poor implementation of reading the device&#8217;s <code>build.prop</code> and other common system files to determine device state and hardware capabilities.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Let&#8217;s break it down per message.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_device_incompatible">1.1. Device Incompatible</h3>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/UBank_NFC_Device.png" alt="UBank NFC Device.png" width="400px">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 1. Device Incompatible</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The incompatibility detected was that the operating system was not greater than "Android 4.4 (KIt Kat)".</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;m running Android 7.1.1, which is well above this requirement.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>From a user&#8217;s perspective, this makes the app look erroneous, which is not good for a banking app.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Not only is there a typo in <code>KIt Kat</code>, the app can&#8217;t even get my Android version? Really?</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_not_supported">1.2. Not Supported</h3>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/UBank_NFC_Not_supported.png" alt="UBank NFC Not supported.png" width="400px">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 2. Not Supported</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This is already iterated above in <a href="#Figure 1">[Figure 1]</a>. I don&#8217;t need to see this again. I&#8217;m already frustrated enough as it is.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_os_compatibility">1.3. OS Compatibility</h3>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/UBank_NFC_OS_Compat.png" alt="UBank NFC OS Compat.png" width="400px">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 3. OS: compatibility</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Failure to detect the correct Android version appears to be the issue here again.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It may be the fact I&#8217;m participating in the Android Beta Channel program, but that is not clear from this message. All I feel as a user is "UBank is <strong>wrong</strong>".</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_cpu">1.4. CPU</h3>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/UBank_NFC_CPU.png" alt="UBank NFC CPU.png" width="400px">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 4. CPU</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So you need an ARM-based CPU to use payments?</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You mean, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nexus_6P#Hardware">Snapdragon ARM Cortex-A57 CPUs</a> that are actually used in my device?</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You can imagine what I&#8217;m thinking as a user at this point. The message actually suggests that I go off to the internet and try hunting for the type of processor my phone uses, just so I can try and troubleshoot this issue?</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_nfc">1.5. NFC</h3>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/UBank_NFC_NFC.png" alt="UBank NFC NFC.png" width="400px">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 5. NFC</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You effing what?</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Not only is my device equipped with an NFC element, it is turned on. Right now.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>"WHY CAN&#8217;T YOU SEE IT?", I yelled at my screen, hoping the developers of the banking app would get a burning sensation on the back of their necks.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_rooted">1.6. Rooted</h3>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/UBank_NFC_Rooted.png" alt="UBank NFC Rooted.png" width="400px">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 6. Rooted</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Yes. Yes! This part of your app truly is Rooted.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>However my phone is not.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Bootloader is unlocked, but I do not have any superuser binary installed on this hardware.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So, <strong>wrong</strong>. Again!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_summary">2. Summary</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I can attempt to summarise this issue as follows:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>the app doesn&#8217;t know about Android 7.1.1 because it isn&#8217;t an officially supported Android release. Yet.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>because there is no record of this Android version in the app&#8217;s database, it can&#8217;t verify the release</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>It takes a best guess about what might be going on, and gets it horribly wrong.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_product_owner">2.1. Product Owner</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>From a Product Owner&#8217;s perspective:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>it doesn&#8217;t match the tone of the rest of the app in the information it provides.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>when a device is analysed and determined not to be compatible, there is <strong>too much</strong> information for the average Android user to parse.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>this screen will probably result in a Help Desk call if users encounter the "Nope" screen like this.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_technical_writer">2.2. Technical Writer</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>From a Technical Writer&#8217;s perspective:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>the copy needs to be reviewed from a spelling and consistency perspective.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>the information needs to be terse, and correct for the audience.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/11/08/U-Bnk-Has-NFC-About-Correct-User-Feedback.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/11/08/U-Bnk-Has-NFC-About-Correct-User-Feedback.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Writing]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Users]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Apps]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Being Switzerland Has Its Advantages]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>"Becoming the Switzerland of your Organisation" may evolve your Technical Writing career into an invaluable interface layer between departments.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Being neutral, and approachable allows folks that may have pre-conceived ideas about other departments drop their guard and open up to reveal sometimes startling revelations about how a product is used. You can then use this information to add value to the products that you document, far beyond simple documentation.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>One recent case where this approach helped tremendously is a situation of "mistaken identity" of a group of options in a User Interface (UI).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The options were part of a larger function in the UI that allowed conditions to be set against certain events. The problem was the group label (let&#8217;s call it <code>Zones</code>) remained constant while the intent of the conditions (let&#8217;s call them <code>Limits</code>) outgrew the UI nomenclature. As I discovered, what started out as a small, logical nomenclature grew into something so overloaded in meaning that it was confusing multiple stakeholders. Worse still, the overloaded meaning was creeping into the codebase.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>With the question about what these fields meant floating around in my sub-conscious, I was on my way back from the bathroom and happened to see one of our internal customers, who showed me how other parts of this system worked during my staff orientation.
I decided to do something at this moment that in hindsight seems fundamental, but is something developers sometimes don&#8217;t feel comfortable doing.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>Don&#8217;t guess <em>why</em> something is the way it is. Ask someone <em>how</em> they actually use it</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>I walked up to his desk.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I asked him if he had five minutes to answer a question I had.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I asked whether he used this area of the UI.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Once he answered "Yes", the mystery began to unravel quite rapidly.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>As I listened to my colleague, it became crystal clear <em>why</em> the <code>Zones</code> list was in that part of the interface, how it was used to set <code>Limits</code>, and why those <code>Limits</code> may have evolved into something no longer accurate in the UI.
Another crucial piece of information was that the <code>Limits</code> functioned more like label metadata for events. The information about the limits were not actually stored in the system itself, but were part of the SME&#8217;s departmental Knowledgebase.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After getting a copy of the limits emailed to me with no more coersion than "Could I get a copy of those, please? It would help me tremendously!", I quite literaly ran upstairs and told my developers what I just learned verbally.
The elation I felt right at that moment—being on the verge of bridging the knowledge gap—is something I never tire of as a Technical Writer.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>As I discovered, some assumptions about how <code>Zones</code> incorrectly related to arbitrary geographical locations had been made in another project, but as I began explaining the relationship was actually just labels for <code>Limits</code> based on the limits document, you could see them shaking their heads in disbelief that no one had asked <em>how</em> rather than <em>why</em>.
Based on this information, minor architectural changes were made to a narrow set of the system to reflect the newly-learned nomenclature and behaviour of these fields in the UI, and how they affected the backend systems linked to them.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>My advice to any Technical Writer wanting to make a difference is simple: be that person that can approach <em>anyone</em> and ask <em>anything</em>.
The culture of the organisation may affect your success with <em>being Switzerland</em>, but the results <em>have their advantages</em> and are worth striving to achieve.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/04/11/Being-Switzerland-Has-Its-Advantages.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/04/11/Being-Switzerland-Has-Its-Advantages.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Writing]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Using SourceTree to Access GitLab]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you want to make the switch to <a href="https://gitlab.com">GitLab</a> from GitHub, or BitBucket Cloud or Server, the way you need to use SourceTree is a little unintuitive as I discovered the other day.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>There is no Account profile you can use to specify your GitLab credentials, so how do you connect?</p>
</div>
<div id="toc" class="toc">
<div id="toctitle" class="title">Table of Contents</div>
<ul class="sectlevel1">
<li><a href="#_how_to_make_the_switch">How To Make The Switch?</a>
<ul class="sectlevel2">
<li><a href="#_generate_an_ssh_key">Generate an SSH Key</a></li>
<li><a href="#_clone_gitlab_repositories_in_sourcetree">Clone GitLab Repositories in SourceTree</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#_bonus_update_local_legacy_repositories_to_point_to_gitlab_repositories_in_sourcetree">Bonus: Update Local Legacy Repositories to Point To GitLab Repositories in SourceTree</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_how_to_make_the_switch">How To Make The Switch?</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The basic process to follow is outlined below:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Generate an SSH Public Key.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Apply the key to your GitLab user profile.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Use the "Clone from URL" SourceTree feature to check out repositories from SourceTree using SSH.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For some folks, that might be enough of a clue to get them on the right path.
If this has not helped you, read on for step-by-step instructions.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_generate_an_ssh_key">Generate an SSH Key</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>GitLab offers SSH as a method to handle authentication between the master and remote repositories.
The advantage of SSH is that you do not need to provide a User Name or Password when you commit work.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>To push content to GitLab using SourceTree, you will need to generate a SSH Public Key using the command-line on your Windows, Mac, or Linux PC.
The following procedures and references will help you achieve this.</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<div class="title">Log onto GitLab UI</div>
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Log onto GitLab.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In the left pane, click <code>Profile Settings</code>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Click <code>SSH Keys</code>.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_retrieve_an_existing_public_key">Retrieve an Existing Public Key</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You&#8217;ll notice that the <code>SSH Keys</code> page displays a banner suggesting you create a SSH Key Pair.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The SSH protocol handles all aspects of verifying who you are using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public-key_cryptography">Public Key Cryptography</a>.
It is a very secure method of authentication, which is why many folks choose it as the only way they interact with GitLab, and other Version Control Systems (VCS).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you have set up SSH for GitHub or another repository before, you can run either of these commands in a terminal to retrieve your public key and enter this into the <code>SSH Keys</code> screen:</p>
</div>
<div class="dlist">
<dl>
<dt class="hdlist1">Windows</dt>
<dd>
<p><code>type %userprofile%\.ssh\id_rsa.pub</code></p>
</dd>
<dt class="hdlist1">Mac or Linux</dt>
<dd>
<p><code>cat ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub</code></p>
</dd>
</dl>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_generate_a_ssh_key_pair">Generate a SSH Key Pair</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you do not get a key after issuing either of these commands, read on for instructions.</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<div class="title">Create a SSH Key Pair</div>
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Load <a href="http://doc.gitlab.com/ce/ssh/README.html" class="bare">http://doc.gitlab.com/ce/ssh/README.html</a> in your browser.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Read the instructions described on this page, and use the commands specified to generate the required key pair.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_apply_the_key_pair_to_your_user_profile">Apply the Key Pair to your User Profile</h4>
<div class="olist arabic">
<div class="title">Apply the Key to Your Profile</div>
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Once you have a public key, click btn:[Add SSH Key].</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Paste the key into the <code>Key</code> field.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Click btn:[Add key] to set the SSH key.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_clone_gitlab_repositories_in_sourcetree">Clone GitLab Repositories in SourceTree</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Because SourceTree does not have a specific protocol defined for GitLab in it&#8217;s Accounts tab, clicking <code>Remotes</code> and selecting from the list of known repositories will not work.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You need to change your approach when cloning repositories from GitLab to the "Clone from URL" method.</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<div class="title">How to Clone a GitLab Repository using SourceTree</div>
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Load <a href="https://gitlab.com" class="bare">https://gitlab.com</a> in your browser.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Navigate to the GitLab repository you want to clone.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Copy the <code>SSH</code> path shown in the screen.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In SourceTree, click menu:New Repository[Clone from URL].</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Paste the copied SSH path into the <code>Source URL</code> field.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Specify the <code>Destination Path</code> and <code>Name</code> as you have done previously.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Click Clone.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The repository is cloned using the SSH protocol and now appears in the Local tab of SourceTree.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_bonus_update_local_legacy_repositories_to_point_to_gitlab_repositories_in_sourcetree">Bonus: Update Local Legacy Repositories to Point To GitLab Repositories in SourceTree</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you are migrating all your repositories over from another VCS to GitLab, chances are you have all the old repositories checked-out to your PC already.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You don&#8217;t need to delete them all and check them out again through GitLab. Update the remote origin to point to the new GitLab SSH path and you&#8217;ll be back in business.</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<div class="title">Change Upstream Repository Information in SourceTree</div>
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Load <a href="https://gitlab.com" class="bare">https://gitlab.com</a> in your browser.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Navigate to the GitLab repository you want to update locally.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Copy the <code>SSH</code> path shown in the screen.</p>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
The SSH path should be the default. If <code>HTTPS</code> is shown, change it to <code>SSH</code> to refresh the URL.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>Open SourceTree.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Click the <code>Local</code> tab to display all locally-tracked repositories.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Double-click on a repository to open the interface for the selected repository.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Click btn:[Settings] (top right of the interface).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In the <code>Remotes</code> group, click on the <code>origin</code> path, and then click btn:[Edit].</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Paste the SSH path you copied from the GitLab UI into this field and then click btn:[Save].</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/03/16/Using-Source-Tree-to-Access-Git-Lab.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/03/16/Using-Source-Tree-to-Access-Git-Lab.html</guid><category><![CDATA[open]]></category><category><![CDATA[ source]]></category><category><![CDATA[ bitbucket]]></category><category><![CDATA[ stash]]></category><category><![CDATA[ gitlab]]></category><category><![CDATA[ vcs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[RAML for Managing the API Lifecycle]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;ve already talked about Tom Johnson&#8217;s podcast series <em>I&#8217;d Rather Be Writing</em>, where he shares his thoughts and experiences about writing API documentation in the burgeoning San Francisco technology and start-up scene.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On a <a href="http://idratherbewriting.com/2015/10/12/spec-driven-design-podcast-michael-stowe/">recent podcast</a>, Tom talked with Michael Stowe, who wrote <em>Undisturbed REST: The guide to designing the perfect API</em>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>They introduced the concept of the RESTful API Modeling Langage (RAML), which you can read more about on <a href="http://raml.org/" class="bare">http://raml.org/</a></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>What makes RAML worth considering is that it is actually a full API lifecycle tool. It lets you design your API design without actually coding anything, but also create a fully functional mock for customers, partners, or internal engineers to review and build from.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If used by the whole organisation, you can avoid a lot of technical debt by getting all parties to agree on the design of the API <strong>before</strong> you task any developers with actually writing the endpoints.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The advantage for documentarians, is that RAML also has our back&#8217;s covered. Because documentation is a crucial part of the API lifecycle, writing the spec for the API from the start bascially means that it is documented.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you are starting out with API technology in your company, consider adopting RAML to control the API lifecycle.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/01/16/RAML-for-Managing-the-API-Lifecycle.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/01/16/RAML-for-Managing-the-API-Lifecycle.html</guid><category><![CDATA[tech writing]]></category><category><![CDATA[ API]]></category><category><![CDATA[ RAML]]></category><category><![CDATA[ podcasts]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[APIs, and why Tech Writers need to know about them.]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;m finding more and more that consuming podcasts is a more accessible way to learn about things. I find I don&#8217;t have time to sit down and read a book, but it is easy to put a podcast on while commuting or walking around at lunch.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I still get a knowledge transfer from the podcast, and in many cases it prompts me to do some targeted research on the discussion points after consuming the podcast.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Case in point: Tom Johnson and his <a href="http://idratherbewriting.com/category-podcasts/">I&#8217;d Rather Be Writing podcast</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I discovered Tom Johnson by doing a search for <code>Technical Writing</code> in <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=au.com.shiftyjelly.pocketcasts&amp;hl=en">Pocketcasts</a> (or iTunes if you are in the Apple ecosystem). He really is the only Tech Writer pushing Podcast content up.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Tom works in the San Francisco Silicon Valley area, which is seeing a strong trend upward with companies desperate for Technical Writers capable of writing Application Programming Interface (API) documentation.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>His podcasts almost always focus on the emerging trends of API documentation, and have honestly been invaluable for me in Australia. I feel that Australia really isn&#8217;t seeing the same upward trend in API documentation that the Silicon Valley Tech Writing industry is seeing, mainly due to the lack of a vibrant (and concentrated) start-up scene.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Nearly every start-up wants to expose their killer app or hosted service to API endpoints, so developers can consume the start-up&#8217;s service, and implement their technology into apps and websites. The requirement to document these endpoints (in many cases both internal <strong>and</strong> external) form a crucial part of a start-up&#8217;s product offering.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Tom&#8217;s content is incredibly useful. And in the case of the work I&#8217;m doing at Ladbrokes, it is also timely. I&#8217;m working with engineers that work on an internal API. I&#8217;ve also been able to recommend and shortlist API frameworks like <a href="http://swagger.io/">Swagger</a>, <a href="https://stripe.com/docs/api#intro">Stripe</a>, and begin to have intelligent conversations with devs about how APIs work.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;m even taking inspiration from Tom&#8217;s <a href="http://idratherbewriting.com/2015/12/29/trends-technical-writing-2016/">2016 Tech Writing Predictions</a> post and starting to learn a programming language.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So if you are a Tech Writer that is oblivious to what APIs are, do yourself a favour and check out Tom&#8217;s past-casts. Even the old ones are great, because they were captured at a time when Tom was learning about APIs as well. It is amazing to see how far this part of Technical Writing has evolved since Tom&#8217;s first podcast.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/01/16/APIs-and-why-Tech-Writers-need-to-know-about-them.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/01/16/APIs-and-why-Tech-Writers-need-to-know-about-them.html</guid><category><![CDATA[tech writing]]></category><category><![CDATA[ API]]></category><category><![CDATA[ podcasts]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[New Year, New Domain.]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_happy_new_year">Happy New Year!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It&#8217;s taken me five months, but I&#8217;ve finally activated my new domain name.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The old <a href="http://jaredmorgs.github.io" class="bare">http://jaredmorgs.github.io</a> site should now redirect to the new <a href="http://jaredleonmorgan.net" class="bare">http://jaredleonmorgan.net</a> site.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Any other sites like the previous home of the Pinball Arcade Android Users Guide (<a href="http://jaredmorgs.github.io/Pinball_Arcade_Users_Guide_Android" class="bare">http://jaredmorgs.github.io/Pinball_Arcade_Users_Guide_Android</a>) should also switch over automatically.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_static_site_experimentation">Static Site Experimentation</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I had been experimenting with a few different static site generators during this time. I&#8217;ve tried Middleman and Awestruct (although not in a very concerted way), and I drifted back to the Jekyll Asciidoctor Quickstart as well, trying out the <a href="http://lanyon.getpoole.com/">Lanyon</a> theme.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>My goal to set up a web page that let me both show my Resume in a single location, and to continue to offer a blog service.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_which_static_site_generator_won">Which Static Site Generator Won?</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The solution I&#8217;ve chosen? <a href="http://hubpress.io/">HubPress</a>!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Even though HubPress is one year old this February 2016 (give or take a few months), I still love what this static site generator has done for both the adoption of AsciiDoc and the GitHub Pages static site movement.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>There are some pretty wonderful static sites out there using HubPress as their backbone.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I think with a few tweaks to page layouts in Ghost themes, I should be able to add the Documentation and Resume areas I need into HubPress and continue to use HubPress to manage page content authoring.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/01/12/New-Year-New-Domain.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/01/12/New-Year-New-Domain.html</guid><category><![CDATA[2016]]></category><category><![CDATA[ open source]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[HubPress, CNAME, and `A` Records]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you want to use a custom domain in HubPress, it is pretty easy to do it. The trick is knowing about the importance of an <code>A</code> DNS record pointing to some specific GitHub IP addresses.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_step_1_get_a_domain">Step 1 - Get a Domain</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I chose Dreamhost for my domain name registrar, based on some testimonials.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Pay for a domain and once it is registered and parked, you can continue.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_step_2_add_cname_to_hubpress">Step 2 - Add CNAME to HubPress</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Open the HubPress Admin Console</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Click <code>Settings</code>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In the <code>CNAME</code> field, type in your domain name. You don&#8217;t need the <code>www</code> prefix.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Save your changes.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_step_3_add_an_a_record_through_your_host">Step 3 - Add an A Record through your Host</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Thanks to the HubPress founder, Anthonny, he found a <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/20483041/5778580">Stack Overflow Q&amp;A</a> that worked perfectlly with Dreamhost.</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<div class="title">How to add an A Record for GitHub Pages</div>
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Go to <span class="menuseq"><span class="menu">Domains</span>&#160;&#9656; <span class="menuitem">Manage Domains</span></span> in your webpanel.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Locate <code>yournewdomain.com</code>, and click <code>Edit</code> in the Actions column.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Scroll to the bottom of the webpanel and switch to "DNS Only" hosting.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Return to <span class="menuseq"><span class="menu">Domains</span>&#160;&#9656; <span class="menuitem">Manage Domains</span></span> in your webpanel.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Click the <code>DNS</code> link below <code>yournewdomain.com</code>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Add an <code>A</code> record:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Name = (blank, nothing)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Type = <code>A</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Value = <code>192.30.252.153</code></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
The latest list of IP addresses is available from <a href="https://help.github.com/articles/tips-for-configuring-an-a-record-with-your-dns-provider/#configuring-an-a-record-with-your-dns-provider">this GitHub Help article</a>
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The steps—and menu transitions—may differ from provider to provider, but the important thing is to get those GitHub IP addresses added to each <code>A</code> record. Once you do that, your domain will redirect perfectly.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you are using GitHub to host any other static sites that used your old <code>username.github.io</code> address, they will automatically redirect over to <code>yournewdomain.com</code> and maintain their absolute path, which is pretty neat. No dead links for your disparate sites that may have got quite a following. Now all under the one managed domain.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/01/12/HubPress-CNAME-and-A-Records.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2016/01/12/HubPress-CNAME-and-A-Records.html</guid><category><![CDATA[hubpress]]></category><category><![CDATA[ hosting]]></category><category><![CDATA[ domain]]></category><category><![CDATA[ CNAME]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sometimes You Need To Pay It Forward]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>When you work for the <em>"Defining Open Source Software Company of the 21st Century"</em>, you get a different sense of gravity for the work you do. Regardless of the work you do, your contributions have a impact on the wider Open Source community. In my case, it was Technical Writing. In other jobs, what you&#8217;re about to read might be contained in an internal email, but doing that would not embody the idea of <em>Defaulting to Open</em>, which Red Hat is proud to foster as a company. For this reason, I&#8217;ve shared my thoughts about working at Red Hat right here.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_the_beginning">The Beginning</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I got a real crash course introduction to Open Source when I started at Red Hat over six years ago. I was put into a project called Mobicents, which was a recently acquired project as part of the JBoss acquisition. This was a team of veteran open source collaborators.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And here I was: a total n00b to Open Source. Not just the idea of what a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meritocracy">meritocracy</a> was, but I&#8217;d never even used Linux before. I remember getting walked through how to do something basic like <code>ls -la</code> and having serious issues with stuff like spacing in the command, and understanding how tab completion in the terminal worked. And executing commands in a terminal (what, no GUI for this?) was as alien as learning Japanese to me.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_the_middle">The Middle</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It turns out that the challenge working out some pretty tough documentation issues as a n00b&#8212;&#8203;including some aspects of project procedural change management&#8212;&#8203;was the best grounding I could have had in my introduction to Open Source. I went on to manage many other Middleware docs projects including Red Hat JBoss EAP (including it&#8217;s Common Criteria certification), Red Hat JBoss Operations Network, Red Hat Enterprise MRG, Red Hat JBoss Portal, and some other projects that were slotted in when some of the other projects were in a quiet period.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;ve met some amazing and inspiring people throughout my career. There are likely too many to mention here in this post, but if you are reading this as a Red Hatter (either current or alumni) you are counted among one of those people.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_the_end">The End</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Red Hat is a place where excellence resides. For those folks that decide to move on, that excellence stays with them as they share what they&#8217;ve learned with other people who may not know that much about Open Source.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;ve made the decision to transition from an Associate to Alumni. I&#8217;ve been handed a compelling opportunity in the Online Betting market here in Brisbane to set up documentation tooling, processes, and internal community.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It&#8217;s a big challenge, but I&#8217;m ready to tackle it head-on thanks to the skills (both hard and soft) I&#8217;ve learned during my tenure at Red Hat.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_appendix_a_open_source_and_your_career">Appendix A: Open Source and Your Career</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Folks reading this will probably know this already: Open Source is a career enabler. <em>Defaulting to Open</em> in everything you do will not only make you a better writer, but it will add serious kudos to your professional profile.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Volunteering your time in projects on GitHub showcases your work in a portfolio of sorts. Taking initiative to shape a fledgling GitHub project&#8217;s documentation may lead you down a path you never expected. It&#8217;s been great working with GitHub developers on projects that are relevant to the documentation technology we use here at Red Hat (like AsciiDoc, and Asciidoctor).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After seeing what is possible with Open Source, there is <strong>no way</strong> I&#8217;d go back to proprietary unless there was no other Open Source solution.<sup class="footnote">[<a id="_footnoteref_1" class="footnote" href="#_footnote_1" title="View footnote.">1</a>]</sup></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_appendix_b_the_end_for_real_this_time">Appendix B: The End (for real this time)</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>There is no such thing as "goodbye". It&#8217;s more like "see you later".</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>See you later, Red Hat. It&#8217;s been a wild ride, and I wouldn&#8217;t have it any other way.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="footnotes">
<hr>
<div class="footnote" id="_footnote_1">
<a href="#_footnoteref_1">1</a>. And lets face it: that is very unlikely
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/07/17/Sometimes-You-Need-To-Pay-It-Forward.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/07/17/Sometimes-You-Need-To-Pay-It-Forward.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Red Hat]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Open Source]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Career]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Opportunity]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How To Delete Old Category Labels from Google Groups]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Something that has been puzzling me for a while is how Tags and Categories labels are displayed in Google Groups. I&#8217;ve had a breakthrough today with deleting a whole stack of Category labels which were impossible to delete through the Tags menu.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_problem">Problem</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You originally enabled Categories in Google Groups, but found they didn&#8217;t work for your particular community.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You switched over to Tags, and created some custom labels for the tags. But the old Category labels are present in your Tags page, and you can&#8217;t delete them.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Every time you click on the <code>[X]</code> button beside each Category label, then Save the page, the labels come back again.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>"WTF Google", you curse.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_solution">Solution</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>To delete the old Category labels, you need to first delete them in the Categories menu. This is so unintuitive, and a terrible UX. The reason why it is terrible is that there are no clues that this is what you need to do. And the Google Group help gives you absolutely <em>no clue</em> about</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Open the Google Group managment console.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Open the Settings &#8658; Categories view.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Delete <strong>all</strong> the old Category labels by clicking the <code>[X]</code> button beside each Category.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Open the Settings &#8658; Tags view.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Delete the unwanted Category labels by clicking the '[X]` button beside each Tag label.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_additional_info">Additional Info</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I have to say this confused me for over half a year as to why I couldn&#8217;t go into Settings &#8658; Tags and delete the old Category labels. There was no Info message to suggest that these tags are borne from Categories and you need to go into Categories and completely delete them.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I guess you could argue that you should choose one metadata strategy and stick with it, but for my community that I manage, experimentation was the only way to determine this.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;d suggest that Google Groups team needs to consider this particular UX issue, and work around it with some sort of alert.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/07/14/How-To-Delete-Old-Category-Labels-from-Google-Groups.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/07/14/How-To-Delete-Old-Category-Labels-from-Google-Groups.html</guid><category><![CDATA[google groups]]></category><category><![CDATA[ labels]]></category><category><![CDATA[ tags]]></category><category><![CDATA[ categories]]></category><category><![CDATA[ delete]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Retrofit UI Commands in The Pinball Arcade using NVidia Gamepad Mapper]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_summary">Summary</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;ve discovered a way to get basic UI controls in The Pinball Arcade, which lets you access almost all UI buttons relevant from starting the app, selecting a table, starting the game, then exiting all the way back to the Android Home Screen.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The only thing you can&#8217;t do cleanly is scroll the table carousel, but you can implement a mouse swipe that gets around it. It&#8217;s not as clean as I would have like though.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_pre_requisites">Pre-requisites</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You need to have a Shield Tablet and Shield Tablet Controller to use this solution.</p>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
It it not possible to do this with a normal gamepad mapper program that requires a rooted device to access the touchscreen emulation framework. <strong>Unless</strong> the program has multiple pages available for keymaps. I&#8217;m not certain that other apps like SixAxis feature this function.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I was able to do this because the NVidia Shield Gamepad Mapper software allows you to create separate <em>Pages</em> that allow you to break up control schemes based on button presses. You&#8217;ll see what I mean by this when you look at the images and the button labels.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_mapping">Mapping</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Get this mapping set by doing the following:</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Turn on the Tablet Controller</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Open Pinball Arcade</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Long press the <code>|&gt;</code> button on the controller to open the Gamepad Mapper.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Tap the Cloud Download symbol to review the available profiles.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Select the profile created by <code>Jared Morgan</code>.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_mapping_choices">Mapping Choices</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I put my UX hat on and tried to emulate the menu selection patterns I saw briefly in the PS3/PS4 version I have access to in the Games Room at work. The reason I did this was to ensure I had a consistent mapping between primary and secondary button commands. Primary buttons traverse the user through the menu whereas secondary buttons reverse the transition.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Here are the mappings in pictorial form.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_splash_screen">Splash Screen</h4>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/TPA_UI/1-Splash_Screen.png" alt="Splash Screen Mapping">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 1. Splash Screen</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>A</code> will get past the initial splash screen and take you to the Main Menu</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_main_menu">Main Menu</h4>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/TPA_UI/2-Main_Screen.png" alt="Main Menu Screen Mapping">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 2. Main Menu</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>A</code> will take you to the Table Carousel.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>B</code> will take you to the Tournaments menu.</p>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
I need to do more work on the Tournament UI commands, and I couldn&#8217;t at the time of writing because there wasn&#8217;t an active tournament running.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_table_carousel">Table Carousel</h4>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/TPA_UI/3-Table_Carousel.png" alt="Table Carousel Mapping">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 3. Table Carousel</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>A</code> takes you to the Table Flyover screen.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>B</code> takes to back to the Main Menu.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Unfortunatley you will need to use your finger here to scroll the carousel unless you implement a Mouse Gesture by dragging the "Pointy Finger" element onto the carousel and setting a button to trigger the mouse click so you can tap and drag. Really cludgy, but it is the only way to get around this UX issue.</p>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock important">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-important" title="Important"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
If FarSight implemented carousel scrolling using the D-pad, that would make life much, much easier here. Hint, hint. ;-)
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_table_flyover">Table Flyover</h4>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/TPA_UI/4-Flyover.png" alt="Flyover Mapping">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 4. Table Flyover</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>A</code> starts the game and enters Game Mode.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>B</code> takes to back to the Table Carousel.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/TPA_UI/5-Game_Mode.png" alt="Game Mode Mapping">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 5. Game Mode</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>B</code> opens the Options menu (also called the Pause menu).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>X</code> cycles through the views (both table and plunger). Long pressing this button locks the view from scrolling in table views.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_pause_menu">Pause Menu</h4>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/TPA_UI/6-Pause_Menu.png" alt="Game Mode Mapping">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 6. Pause Menu</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>A</code> returns you back to Game Mode.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>B</code> opens the Quit Table menu.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_quit_table_menu">Quit Table Menu</h4>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/TPA_UI/7-Quit_Confirm.png" alt="Quit Table Menu">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 7. Quit Table Menu</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>A</code> quits the game and returns you to the Table Flyover.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>B</code> returns you to the Pause menu.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I thought long and hard about making <code>A</code> the priority here. Normally if you are going to make the user lose progress, you should make the priority button take the user back to safety (in this case the Pause menu). Because the previous menu used the secondary button to access the quit menu, I determined this would be considered a genuine user action, and not something a user would do by accident.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/03/22/Retrofit-UI-Commands-in-The-Pinball-Arcade-using-NVidia-Gamepad-Mapper.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/03/22/Retrofit-UI-Commands-in-The-Pinball-Arcade-using-NVidia-Gamepad-Mapper.html</guid><category><![CDATA[The Pinball Arcade]]></category><category><![CDATA[ NVidia]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Shield Tablet]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Gamepad Mapper]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blog Easily with GitHub Pages and AsciiDoc using HubPress]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_summary">Summary</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>There&#8217;s a new way to blog using GitHub Pages and AsciiDoc:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>No PC required</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Blog on your tablet or phablet.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>No software to install.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>An internet connection is all you need.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>No Gemfiles to install and configure.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>No Git commands to master.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://hubpress.io/">HubPress</a> lets you free yourself from heavy configuration, provides a real-time editing environment, rich social media configuration, and a variety of baked-in styles. But most importantly, it is one of the only forkable blog offerings that has made the wise decision to use the <a href="https://github.com/asciidoctor/asciidoctor.js">AsciiDoctor </a> Javascript port to provide tech bloggers far greater control over how they structure blog posts.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_why_asciidoc">Why AsciiDoc?</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you love writing about technology, and love to make complex instructions with code samples and detailed tables, you would have already found that you have to make a fair few sacrifices with Markdown posts.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Enter AsciiDoc (or more accurately, AsciiDoctor).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>AsciiDoctor&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;which was championed by former Red Hat alumni <a href="https://github.com/mojavelinux">Dan Allen</a>&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;builds upon the already fantastic <a href="http://asciidoc.org/">AsciiDoc</a> by adding a toolchain and various compatibility layers.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>How this affects blog writers is that you don&#8217;t have to kludge your way around the deficiencies of Markdown, and you can get on with the task of writing rich blog posts with complex procedures and code samples.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_getting_started">Getting Started</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you want to give HubPress a try you need to have the following:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>A free <a href="https://github.com">GitHub</a> Account</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A device with a web browser.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_installing_hubpress">Installing HubPress</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Once you have a GitHub account, continue to the <a href="https://github.com/HubPress/hubpress.io/blob/master/README.adoc">HubPress Setup Instructions</a> and follow the steps to set up the blog.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The terse instructions are:</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Fork the HubPress repository.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Make minor changes to the forked repository.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Log onto the HubPress management console.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Customise your blog to your liking.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Write and publish your first blog post in AsciiDoc.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_updating_hubpress">Updating HubPress</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Because HubPress is hosted on GitHub, you can do an update by pulling down the latest changes from the HubPress master repository.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>To learn how to do this correctly (there&#8217;s a trick to it the first time you pull changes from upstream), you can watch this video I created explaining the process.</p>
</div>
<div class="videoblock">
<div class="content">
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KCylB780zSM?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_embedding_images">Embedding Images</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You don&#8217;t even need to use a Git client or app to push images to your blog. Just use GitHub Issues, or link to issues from your cloud backup provider. Watch this video to learn how to do this.</p>
</div>
<div class="videoblock">
<div class="content">
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KoaGU91qJv8?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/03/15/Blog-Easily-with-GitHub-Pages-and-AsciiDoc-using-HubPress.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/03/15/Blog-Easily-with-GitHub-Pages-and-AsciiDoc-using-HubPress.html</guid><category><![CDATA[HubPress]]></category><category><![CDATA[ AsciiDoc]]></category><category><![CDATA[ AsciiDoctor]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Package Messages FAILED when Using Fedora fedup System Upgrade Tool]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After doing something pretty stupid with gParted and LVM last night, I find myself reinstalling Fedora 20 today. I&#8217;ve found a fix to the FAILED package messages you get if you have tried running <code>fedup</code> a few times trying to upgrade.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_temp_caches">Temp Caches</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The <code>fedup</code> tool creates a temporary upgrade cache in <code>/var/cache/system-upgrade/</code>. If you are seeing any strange behavior with <code>fedup</code> as it attempts to download packages, you might want to move into this directory and delete all data.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Deleting the data allowed me to successfully upgrade to Fedora 22.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/03/12/Package-Messages-FAILED-when-Using-Fedora-fedup-System-Upgrade-Tool.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/03/12/Package-Messages-FAILED-when-Using-Fedora-fedup-System-Upgrade-Tool.html</guid><category><![CDATA[fedora]]></category><category><![CDATA[ fedup]]></category><category><![CDATA[ FAILED]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building RHQ API Docs using Maven and Fedora 21]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Stand Back: I&#8217;m Going To Use Maven</p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<div class="attribution">
&#8212; @jaredmorgs
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Some might say these words are a dangerous statement to make.  I went down the path of installing the Maven build system on Fedora 21. Based on my prior experience, I thought it was going to be a trip. To my surprise and delight, I managed to get it working much quicker than I had first thought.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The second installment of my Maven journey wasn&#8217;t as smooth as I would have liked. But as you&#8217;ll read, there is progress being made.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_install_maven">Install Maven</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://maven.apache.org/download.cgi">Maven</a> is a build system that practically all JBoss Products use in the upstream.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The great thing is that it&#8217;s easy to install on Fedora.</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code>sudo yum install maven</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_troubleshoot_maven">Troubleshoot Maven</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_check_the_jdk">Check the JDK</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After you install the package, running <code>mvn --version</code> will likely cause something like the following message to display.</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">mvn --version
Error: JAVA_HOME is not defined correctly.
  We cannot execute /usr/java/jdk1.7.0_17/bin/java</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So what now? Well, maven requires a Java Development Kit. As you can see I <strong>have</strong> a JDK installed. Pffff.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_check_the_path_in_bashrc">Check the PATH in .bashrc</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Suggestions on StackOverflow lead me to believe that all I needed to do was set JAVA_HOME to the correct JDK.</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">export JAVA_HOME=/usr/lib/jvm/java-1.8.0-openjdk</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>1.8.0 is the latest Oracle JDK on Fedora 21. That wasn&#8217;t enough though. I needed to also set PATH in my .bashrc file. <strong>This is where the problem was for me</strong>: I had an old JDK declared in the .bashrc file that had been carried over from previous versons of my OS as I upgraded.</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">## Environment Variables

export JAVA_HOME=/usr/java/jdk1.7.0_17
PATH=$JAVA_HOME/bin/java:$PATH
export PATH</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I changed this to the following:</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">## Environment Variables

export JAVA_HOME=/usr/lib/jvm/java-1.8.0-openjdk
PATH=$JAVA_HOME/bin/java:$PATH
export PATH</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This allowed me to execute <code>mvn --version</code> and get the following output:</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">mvn --version
OpenJDK 64-Bit Server VM warning: ignoring option MaxPermSize=512m; support was removed in 8.0
Apache Maven 3.2.2 (NON-CANONICAL_2014-06-19T11:19:24_mockbuild; 2014-06-19T21:19:24+10:00)
Maven home: /usr/share/maven
Java version: 1.8.0_31, vendor: Oracle Corporation
Java home: /usr/lib/jvm/java-1.8.0-openjdk-1.8.0.31-3.b13.fc21.x86_64/jre
Default locale: en_US, platform encoding: UTF-8
OS name: "linux", version: "3.18.5-201.fc21.x86_64", arch: "amd64", family: "unix"</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This verifies that the basic Maven install works as expected.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_build_the_api_docs">Build the API Docs!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Well. Colour me surprised.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I am now able to continue on with what I wanted to do in the first place: download the RHQ project Git Repo, and build the API Docs. Getting Maven installed and functioning is not nearly as hard as I remembered. Maybe that has a bit to do with my experience at Red Hat. Maybe it has a bit to do with improvements made to Maven over the years since I last used it.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Tune in to the <a href="http://jaredmorgs.github.io/2015/02/16/Build-API-Docs-for-the-RHQ-Project.html">next episode</a> for how that went&#8230;&#8203;</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/02/16/Building-RHQ-API-Docs-using-Maven-and-Fedora-21.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/02/16/Building-RHQ-API-Docs-using-Maven-and-Fedora-21.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Apache Maven]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Fedora 21]]></category><category><![CDATA[ .bashrc]]></category><category><![CDATA[ JAVA_HOME]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Build API Docs for the RHQ Project]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Granted, this blog post will only likely interest the following audience:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Red Hat associates.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Folks using the upstream RHQ project.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Folks interested in techniques for generating API docs using Maven.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>There are two parts to this post:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>The Original Process</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>This covers the steps I took to build RHQ in a hope that others will benefit from it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Some interesting take-aways about what happens when you forget to provide pre-requisite content in a procedure.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Actual Process</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>When we get to this point, I&#8217;ll put the actual procedure you need to follow to produce the API docs.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_the_original_process">The Original Process</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The original process was:</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p><code>$ yum install maven</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ git clone <a href="https://github.com/rhq-project/rhq.git" class="bare">https://github.com/rhq-project/rhq.git</a> jon</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ cd jon</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ cd modules/enterprise/server/jar</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ mvn -Ddocgen install  (or compile)</code></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But after five attempts lasting over three days, I now know this is misleading to say the least.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_first_attempt_no_success">First Attempt: No Success</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I ran the steps in the process, and sat back with a cuppa tea&#8230;&#8203;</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Note the build time&#8230;&#8203;</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">Downloaded: http://repo.maven.apache.org/maven2/org/mockito/mockito-all/1.9.0/mockito-all-1.9.0.jar (1461 KB at 76.0 KB/sec)
Downloaded: http://repo.maven.apache.org/maven2/org/testng/testng/6.5.2/testng-6.5.2.jar (701 KB at 36.4 KB/sec)
[INFO] ------------------------------------------------------------------------
[INFO] BUILD FAILURE
[INFO] ------------------------------------------------------------------------
[INFO] Total time: 15:13 min
[INFO] Finished at: 2015-02-16T10:00:51+10:00
[INFO] Final Memory: 19M/242M
[INFO] ------------------------------------------------------------------------
[ERROR] Failed to execute goal on project rhq-enterprise-server: Could not resolve dependencies for project org.rhq:rhq-enterprise-server:ejb:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT: The following artifacts could not be resolved: org.rhq:rhq-enterprise-comm:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT, org.rhq:rhq-enterprise-server-xml-schemas:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT, org.rhq:rhq-core-domain:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT, org.rhq:rhq-cassandra-schema:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT, org.rhq:rhq-core-plugin-api:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT, org.rhq:rhq-core-client-api:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT, org.rhq:rhq-core-dbutils:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT, org.rhq:safe-invoker:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT, org.rhq:rhq-common-drift:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT, org.rhq:rhq-server-metrics:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT, org.rhq:rhq-cassandra-util:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT, org.rhq:rhq-jboss-as-dmr-client:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT, org.rhq:test-utils:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT, org.rhq.helpers:rest-docs-generator:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT, org.rhq:rhq-core-domain:jar:tests:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT: Could not find artifact org.rhq:rhq-enterprise-comm:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT in sonatype-snapshots (https://oss.sonatype.org/content/repositories/snapshots/) -&gt; [Help 1]
[ERROR]
[ERROR] To see the full stack trace of the errors, re-run Maven with the -e switch.
[ERROR] Re-run Maven using the -X switch to enable full debug logging.
[ERROR]
[ERROR] For more information about the errors and possible solutions, please read the following articles:
[ERROR] [Help 1] http://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/MAVEN/DependencyResolutionException</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I can&#8217;t really complain about this though: the first time you build a Maven project, you can expect it to take a long time as it downloads the required dependencies.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The error at this stage suggests I need to build the required dependencies myself before the DocGen tool will work.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>No worries!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_second_attempt_build_deps">Second Attempt: Build Deps?</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Luckily the folks in the RHQ project have made dependency building as simple as possible.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the root of the project there is this script:</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><code>$ ./build-deps.sh</code></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Run this script, and it orchestrates the dependency build process for the project. This type of automation is great for folks wanting to easily build the project. Great work RHQ team!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The script and the resulting process completed successfully, and I thought I was ready to run DocGen.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Not. So. Fast.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It turns out that this script builds the Cassandra dependencies. These are unrelated to the DocGen process, but there was nothing in the repo to tell me that.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_third_attempt_run_doggen_at_project_root">Third Attempt: Run DogGen at Project Root?</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I ran <code>$ mvn -Ddocgen install</code> and got this result.</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">[INFO] ------------------------------------------------------------------------
[INFO] Building RHQ Enterprise Server JAR 4.14.0-SNAPSHOT
[INFO] ------------------------------------------------------------------------
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-enterprise-comm:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-enterprise-server-xml-schemas:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-core-domain:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-cassandra-schema:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-core-plugin-api:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-core-client-api:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-core-dbutils:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:safe-invoker:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-common-drift:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-server-metrics:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-cassandra-util:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-jboss-as-dmr-client:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:test-utils:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq.helpers:rest-docs-generator:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-core-domain:jar:tests:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Still no bueno with DocGen. :(</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>At this point, I hit a dead end. And when I hit a dead end, I start doing <em>questionable</em> things in hope that I can resolve the issue.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I thought perhaps the following step was wrong:</p>
</div>
<div class="literalblock">
<div class="content">
<pre>4) `$ cd modules/enterprise/server/jar`</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I though to myself "Perhaps I need to execute <code>$ mvn -Ddocgen install</code> at the project root?"</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I executed the command at project root and things certainly looked promising. Maven began downloading a whole stack of dependencies that related to the platform. But as a Maven n00b, I learned after 11 minutes that this was a false sense of security. By executing the DocGen command at the project root, maven took the configuration in the root pom.xml file and began compiling the <strong>entire project</strong>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Should have trusted the instructions on that one. But the positive out of this was I got a refresher about how Maven works. Lets chalk this up to experience.</p>
</div>
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Build only what you need, at the level you need.</p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<div class="attribution">
&#8212; a Maven Warlock Lvl10
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Sagely advice for sure.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_fourth_attempt_branch_not_master">Fourth Attempt: Branch Not Master!</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After contacting the RHQ team (overnight - very quick response), they could see that I was running these commands against <code>master</code>. It turns out I needed to run DocGen on a branch and not master. They also gave me the tip that I could cut down the build time by specifying <code>-DskipTests</code> and possibly <code>-Dmaven.test.skip</code></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Based on this feedback, I hypothesised the updated steps to be:</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p><code>$ yum install maven</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ git clone <a href="https://github.com/rhq-project/rhq.git" class="bare">https://github.com/rhq-project/rhq.git</a> jon</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ cd jon</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ git checkout -b release/<em>[latest_branch]</em></code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ cd modules/enterprise/server/jar</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ mvn -Ddocgen compile -DskipTests -Dmaven.test.skip</code> (initially, then for subsequent builds)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ mvn -Ddocgen install -DskipTests -Dmaven.test.skip</code></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Still no bueno with DocGen. :(</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I ran the compile command first, which failed. I then, out of desperation, ran the install command. It produced the same result:</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">[jmorgan@jmorgan-bne-redhat-com jar] (release/jon3.3.x) $ mvn -Ddocgen compile -DskipTests -Dmaven.test.skip
OpenJDK 64-Bit Server VM warning: ignoring option MaxPermSize=512m; support was removed in 8.0
[INFO] Scanning for projects...
[INFO]
[INFO] ------------------------------------------------------------------------
[INFO] Building RHQ Enterprise Server JAR 4.14.0-SNAPSHOT
[INFO] ------------------------------------------------------------------------
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-enterprise-comm:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-enterprise-server-xml-schemas:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-core-domain:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-core-plugin-api:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-core-client-api:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-core-dbutils:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:safe-invoker:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-common-drift:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-server-metrics:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq:rhq-jboss-as-dmr-client:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[WARNING] The POM for org.rhq.helpers:rest-docs-generator:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT is missing, no dependency information available
[INFO] ------------------------------------------------------------------------
[INFO] BUILD FAILURE
[INFO] ------------------------------------------------------------------------
[INFO] Total time: 1.557 s
[INFO] Finished at: 2015-02-17T10:32:18+10:00
[INFO] Final Memory: 18M/437M
[INFO] ------------------------------------------------------------------------
[ERROR] Failed to execute goal on project rhq-enterprise-server: Could not resolve dependencies for project org.rhq:rhq-enterprise-server:ejb:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT: The following artifacts could not be resolved:
org.rhq:rhq-enterprise-comm:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT,
org.rhq:rhq-enterprise-server-xml-schemas:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT,
org.rhq:rhq-core-domain:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT,
org.rhq:rhq-core-plugin-api:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT,
org.rhq:rhq-core-client-api:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT,
org.rhq:rhq-core-dbutils:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT,
org.rhq:safe-invoker:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT,
org.rhq:rhq-common-drift:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT,
org.rhq:rhq-server-metrics:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT,
org.rhq:rhq-jboss-as-dmr-client:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT,
org.rhq.helpers:rest-docs-generator:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT:
Failure to find org.rhq:rhq-enterprise-comm:jar:4.14.0-SNAPSHOT in https://oss.sonatype.org/content/repositories/snapshots/ was cached in the local repository, resolution will not be reattempted until the update interval of sonatype-snapshots has elapsed or updates are forced -&gt; [Help 1]
[ERROR]</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_fifth_attempt_why_pre_requisites_matter_in_docs">Fifth Attempt: Why Pre-requisites Matter in Docs</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So, I got a response from the RHQ list and a key piece of info was missing:</p>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock warning">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-warning" title="Warning"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
You need to <strong>build RHQ first</strong> before you can <strong>build the API docs</strong>. You also need to do it on <code>master</code>, not <code>release/jon3.3.x</code>.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Some choice expletives were uttered by me at this point&#8230;&#8203; This was not mentioned anywhere in the internal product doc repositories, in the originally-provided procedure, nor was it implied as a pre-requisite in the upstream docs.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The problem with not setting pre-requisites in documentation mean that if a user gets dumped here by Google, there was no context to say the project needs to be built first. Folks don&#8217;t read a book cover to cover any more. You need to cater for this by telling them basic information like this at every opportunity. Treach each page as page one.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Let&#8217;s revise the procedure with the updated information received today:</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p><code>$ yum install maven</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://docs.jboss.org/author/display/RHQ/Building+RHQ">Build RHQ</a>, which covers the following:</p>
<div class="olist loweralpha">
<ol class="loweralpha" type="a">
<li>
<p>Install JDK</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Install Maven</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Install Git</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Install and Create Database for PostgreSQL</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ git clone <a href="https://github.com/rhq-project/rhq.git" class="bare">https://github.com/rhq-project/rhq.git</a> jon</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ cd jon</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ git checkout -b release/<em>[latest_branch]</em></code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ cd modules/enterprise/server/jar</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ mvn -Ddocgen compile -DskipTests -Dmaven.test.skip</code> (initially, then for subsequent builds)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>$ mvn -Ddocgen install -DskipTests -Dmaven.test.skip</code></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Still no bueno with DocGen. :(</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Up until this point, I&#8217;ve spent two days on this task. I&#8217;ve decided to make lemonade out of my two-day-old lemons and correct the  <a href="https://docs.jboss.org/author/display/RHQ/Generating+Plugin+Documentation">Generating Plugin Documentation</a> community docs to reflect this. I also made changes to three other community pages linked from the <a href="https://docs.jboss.org/author/display/RHQ/Building+RHQ">Building RHQ</a> page doc page with correct information for Fedora 21:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://docs.jboss.org/author/display/RHQ/Advanced+Build+Notes">Advanced Build Notes</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://docs.jboss.org/author/display/RHQ/PostgreSQL">PostgreSQL</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This info will surely prove valuable for community devs that want to experiment with RHQ.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_the_actual_and_correct_process">The Actual (and correct) Process</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This post is getting so long now, I think I&#8217;ll make a separate one.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>There is still quite a path to traverse down before I can comfortably say "generating RHQ API docs is easy".</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The <a href="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=1192869">BugZilla Bug</a> I raised to capture these challenges will hopefully help the engineers with resolving the issue for me, and for users of the project.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And what&#8217;s even better is that I&#8217;ll be able to update the generation procedures for API documentation for the next time I need to pull the docs out.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/02/16/Build-API-Docs-for-the-RHQ-Project.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/02/16/Build-API-Docs-for-the-RHQ-Project.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Maven]]></category><category><![CDATA[ RHQ]]></category><category><![CDATA[ API Docs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Recycling Fence Palings for Tree Borders]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I had some old treated pine fence palings left over from when I replaced all the side gate palings. My wife suggested I use them to fix up the borders around the trees, so I took her advice and got it done over two weekends.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/Tree_Border_Two.jpg" alt="Tree Border Two.jpg" width="300, height=" height="500"">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 1. The Finished Product</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_would_you_use_wood_that_would_cost_you_nix">Would You Use Wood That Would Cost You Nix?</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>I would</strong>. Seriously, if you can get wood cheap or free, you take it and save some big cash. I could have gone and purchased some new wood from the hardware store, but that would have almost doubled the cost of the job.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The most time consuming part of the job was dressing off the old pine planks, and painting them. They were pretty rough and a mouse sander quickly took care of that.</p>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
If you don&#8217;t have a bunch of palings lying around like I did, you might want to go to your local reclamation yard. There might be some good quality timber you can use there.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_wood_that_wasn_t_free">Wood That Wasn&#8217;t Free</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I did actually fork our for some new timber. The spacers required for the job were cut at the cutting station at Bunnings.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredmorgs.github.io/images/Tree_Border_Palings_Spacers.jpg" alt="Tree Border Palings Spacers.jpg" width="300, height=" height="500"">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 2. Spacers</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I have to say I could have probably done a better job myself regarding size consistency, but at 12 blocks to be cut, paying 50c a cut was worth it. And the size still worked OK, so not a problem.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_free_paint_is_free_except_when_you_run_out_of_undercoat">Free Paint is Free, Except When You Run Out of Undercoat</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredmorgs.github.io/images/Tree_Border_Palings_Painted.jpg" alt="Tree Border Palings Painted.jpg" width="300, height=" height="500"">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 3. Painted Slats</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The paint colour was a water-based interior colour, courtesy of Masters North Lakes, after they gave us a whole stack of mistint tins as part of a Sausage Sizzle Fundraiser we conducted. Our childs' Kindergarten couldn&#8217;t accept them due to the paint not being non-toxic, so we saved this colour specifically for this job, and gave the other tin to them for minor touch-ups around the Kindy.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Becasue this wasn&#8217;t a standard fence paint, I needed to undercoat before painting with two top coats. This quite literally took all weekend last weekend. I <em>nearly</em> had enough undercoat to get the job done, but I had to fork out about $25 for a new tin. Undercoat is a good thing to have around anyhow, so I wan&#8217;t too worried.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_measure_twice_then_check_the_fit_then_cut">Measure Twice, Then Check The Fit, Then Cut</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Even though I measured once, measured twice, I still had some issues with measurements. A quick cut here and there fixed that. I got it mostly right. I had assembly knocked over this morning. The key with this type of thing is to paint the planks first before assembly. Then only cut one end of the plank if you need to make adjustments. This way you don&#8217;t need to repaint the raw edge becasue it is abutted against a painted side.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_all_in_all_not_a_bad_job">All In All, Not A Bad Job</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>All in all, they&#8217;ve come up really nicely. All up, I spent about $100 including some tools I needed for the job. Most of the expense was for the plank of plywood I used to convert my glass-top office desk to a workbench. That paid dividends these two weekends for sure.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/Tree_Border_Two.jpg" alt="Tree Border Two.jpg" width="300, height=" height="500"">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 4. Being Frugal Pays</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/02/15/Recycling-Fence-Palings-for-Tree-Borders.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/02/15/Recycling-Fence-Palings-for-Tree-Borders.html</guid><category><![CDATA[reclaim]]></category><category><![CDATA[ reuse]]></category><category><![CDATA[ recycle]]></category><category><![CDATA[ garden borders]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lobby GitHub for AsciiDoc Support in Jekyll Blogs Hosted on GitHub Pages]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_tl_dr">tl: dr</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Help get the jekyll-asciidoc Converter whitelisted for GitHub Pages, and get native AsciiDoc support in GitHub Pages hosted Blogs!</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Send a support request to <a href="https://github.com/contact">GitHub Support</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Quote the repo name: <code><a href="https://github.com/asciidoctor/jekyll-asciidoc" class="bare">https://github.com/asciidoctor/jekyll-asciidoc</a></code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Tell them why you want AsciiDoc support for your blog.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_background">Background</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;ve been following the work that Dan Allen&#8217;s AsciiDoctor project has been doing recently.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The other day he announced that they were successful in getting the jekyll-asciidoc Converter added to the list of plug-ins on the <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/docs/plugins/">Jekyll Plug-ins Page</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_limitations">Limitations</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The logical next step would be to get this converter whitelisted for GitHub Pages. Folks new to Jekyll could then fork a Jekyll AsciiDoc-aware Git Repo and start blogging directly on mobile devices.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_setup_complexity">Setup Complexity</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Folks that want to try out Jekyll blogging on a mobile device only have the choice of MarkDown if they don&#8217;t have access to a PC. To get Jekyll AsciiDoc support working for a Mobile authoring environment, you need to:</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Use a computer to configure your repo, which for some folks is a deal-breaker.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Configure Ruby and Rubygems.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Install and configure Jekyll.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Configure Travis CI to detect when you commit changes to a branch and build the site.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Only then can you write in .adoc on your mobile device and have the content published to GitHub Pages.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It shouldn&#8217;t be that difficult! The team over at AsciiDoctor are working on a  <a href="https://github.com/asciidoctor/jekyll-asciidoc-quickstart">forkable repo</a> that should take some of the complexity out of working with AsciiDoc on GitHub Pages. Discussion prompting this repo is tracked on <a href="https://github.com/asciidoctor/jekyll-asciidoc/issues/26">Issue 26</a> of the jekyll-asciidoc repository.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In contrast, Barry Clark&#8217;s <a href="https://github.com/barryclark/jekyll-now">jekyll-now</a> project&#8212;&#8203;a fantastic Jekyll blog repo that removes the complexity of Jekyll Set-up and Ruby for new adopters&#8212;&#8203;does it like this:</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Fork the repo: your default blog is live!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Make a few changes to the _config.yml file.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Commit and Push.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Your customised blog is live!</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_complex_blog_post_formatting_issues">Complex Blog Post Formatting Issues</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The problem I&#8217;ve found with MarkDown is the lack of more extensible mark-up is not quite cutting it for some of the more complex posts like <a href="http://jaredmorgs.github.io/using-ffmpeg-to-record-screencasts/" class="bare">http://jaredmorgs.github.io/using-ffmpeg-to-record-screencasts/</a>. This post took me about three hours to get looking right with MarkDown.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>With AsciiDoc, I estimate I could have done it in about 1 hour.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_how_you_can_help">How You Can Help</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you currently use Jekyll to blog, or have tried it in the past but abandoned it, it would be a great time to drive adoption of this documentation solution.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>With the plug-in whitelisted, repos like Barry Clark&#8217;s could be created that "Just Work" and let folks get on with the job of creating blog posts without the config overhead.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/02/10/Lobby-GitHub-for-AsciiDoc-Support-in-Jekyll-Blogs-Hosted-on-GitHub-Pages.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/02/10/Lobby-GitHub-for-AsciiDoc-Support-in-Jekyll-Blogs-Hosted-on-GitHub-Pages.html</guid><category><![CDATA[AsciiDoctor]]></category><category><![CDATA[ GitHub Pages]]></category><category><![CDATA[ jekyll-asciidoc]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Jekyll Blogs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How Social Media Can Open Doors to New Opportunites]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Out of the blue, I received a tweet from <a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/anthonny_q">Anthonny Quérouil</a>. He suggested that if I liked AsciiDoc, I should check out HubPress. I&#8217;m so thankful he reached out to me, because it started me down a fantastic journey of open source collaboration and gave me the ability to write amazingly detailed blog posts directly on my tablet.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_github_blogging_is_great_but">GitHub Blogging is Great! But&#8230;&#8203;</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you love writing about technology, and love to make complex instructions with code samples and detailed tables, you would have already found that you have to make a fair few sacrifices with Markdown posts.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Markdown is natively supported by GitHub Pages because it is supported GitHub wide in all comments, issues, and Readme files. So is AsciiDoc, but not natively on GitHub Page generated blogs. I&#8217;ve done my best to get this changed by lobbying for AsciiDoc support, but I&#8217;m not holding my breath.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_enter_asciidoc_or_more_accurately_asciidoctor">Enter AsciiDoc (or more accurately, AsciiDoctor)</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>AsciiDoctor&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;which was championed by former Red Hat alumni <a href="https://github.com/mojavelinux">Dan Allen</a>&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;builds upon the already fantastic <a href="http://asciidoc.org/">AsciiDoc</a> by adding a toolchain and various compatibility layers.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>How this affects blog writers is that you don&#8217;t have to kludge your way around the deficiencies of Markdown, and you can get on with the task of writing rich blog posts with complex procedures and code samples.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_how_i_got_involved_in_asciidoctor">How I Got Involved in AsciiDoctor</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I became interested in AsciiDoctor recently when the AsciiDoctor team announced they were successful in getting the <a href="https://github.com/asciidoctor/jekyll-asciidoc">jekyll-asciidoc plug-in</a> listed on the supported Converter list on the <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/docs/plugins/">Jekyll Plugins</a> page.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I started collaborating in a docs capacity with the team on a forkable <a href="https://github.com/asciidoctor/jekyll-asciidoc-quickstart">jekyll-asciidoctor Quickstart Blog</a> repo that used JenkinsCI to enable bloggers to initially configure a Jekyll blog with AsciiDoctor support. Once configured, you could set up the JenkinsCI build server to intercept commits on the <code>gh-pages</code> branch of the repository. I was just about to start configuring the repository, and installing all the Ruby dependencies so I could generate a Travis CI key.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_enter_hubpress">Enter HubPress</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>When Anthonny contacted me on twitter, he introduced me to the HubPress project. Being a Technical Writer for Red Hat, I noted that the project README was a little underdone.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So in true open source spirit, I took it upon myself to do a major Pull Request (PR) on the content (only my second PR after contributing to the AsciiDoctor quickstart).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I used the basic config info initially to help me install the system. As I noticed deficiencies, I improved them. After I was happy with the way the docs looked, I created a PR and let Anthonny know.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_help_out_an_open_source_project_today">Help Out An Open Source Project Today</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The thing with Open Source Projects is that they need writers. And if you even do minor tweaks to their docs, they will be so thankful.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You don&#8217;t need to be a Developer to work on a software project. Do you speak another language? Can you write Documentation? Are you great at video production? Are you trained or specialise in UX design?</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>All these skills are incredibly important to a product that is trying to make the best impression to it&#8217;s user base, and increase adoption.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_about_hubpress">About HubPress</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_why_hubpress_rocks">Why HubPress Rocks</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://hubpress.io/">HubPress</a> lets you free yourself from heavy configuration, provides a real-time editing environment, rich social media configuration, and a variety of baked-in styles. But most importantly, it is one of the only forkable blog offerings that has made the wise decision to use the <a href="https://github.com/asciidoctor/asciidoctor.js">AsciiDoctor </a> Javascript port to provide tech bloggers far greater control over how they structure blog posts.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>HubPress is different to other Jekyll GitHub Pages Blogging solutions:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>No PC required</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Blog on your tablet or phablet.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>No software to install.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>An internet connection is all you need.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>No Gemfiles to install and configure.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>No Git commands to master.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you host your images, you can even direct link to them and not have to commit to Git.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_shut_up_and_take_my_money">Shut Up And Take My Money</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Well, you won&#8217;t need to shell out any clams. HubPress is Free!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Head over to <a href="https://github.com/HubPress/hubpress.io/blob/master/README.adoc">the Docs</a> and learn how to set up your blog in only a few clicks.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/02/06/How-Social-Media-Can-Open-Doors-to-New-Opportunites.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/02/06/How-Social-Media-Can-Open-Doors-to-New-Opportunites.html</guid><category><![CDATA[HubPress]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Markdown]]></category><category><![CDATA[ AsciiDoc]]></category><category><![CDATA[ GitHub Pages]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Turning a Shield Tablet US Version into a Rest of World Version]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="toc" class="toc">
<div id="toctitle">Table of Contents</div>
<ul class="sectlevel1">
<li><a href="#_summary">Summary</a></li>
<li><a href="#_why_do_this">Why Do This?</a></li>
<li><a href="#_procedure">Procedure</a>
<ul class="sectlevel2">
<li><a href="#_prerequisites">Prerequisites</a></li>
<li><a href="#_download_the_recovery_image">Download the Recovery Image</a></li>
<li><a href="#_unlock_bootloader_and_flash_recovery">Unlock Bootloader and Flash Recovery</a></li>
<li><a href="#_post_update_boot_time_relax">Post-update Boot Time: Relax!</a></li>
<li><a href="#_install_an_ota_to_get_the_modem_files">Install an OTA to get the Modem Files</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#_you_did_it">You Did It!</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_summary">Summary</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;ve been waiting patiently until NVidia released the Android 5.0 Factory Images in late December 2014 before I even attempted this experiment. This blog post describes how to turn the NVidia Shield LTE Tablet I purchased with the US firmware to a "Rest of World" variant, safely and successfully.</p>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock warning">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-warning" title="Warning"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
I&#8217;ve since found out that while the process does indeed allow you to flash the Rest of World ROM to the device, the modem hardware check done at each boot cycle prevents the RoW modems from being loaded. Some XDA members are looking into ways to force the modem files <em>you</em> want loaded to be installed at boot in <a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=2951111">this thread</a>. Until this is resolved, this post will not allow you to enable RoW modem bands on a US originating device.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_why_do_this">Why Do This?</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Normally, changing a device to a completely different device variant OS is a risky undertaking. But because NVidia have made minimal mods to the AOSP cut of their operating system, you can switch any LTE Shield Tablet to use either the "North America" (wx_na_do) or "Rest of World" (wx-un-do) Android Builds.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>Providing you can get a hold of a Rest-of-World OTA update that contains an updated modem stack</strong>, folks like me in Australia can put a local SIM in my tablet and use 4G data on the go. If I kept the firmware as "US Only" I would not be able to use my local carrier&#8217;s 4G spectrums, which differ from the USA.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_procedure">Procedure</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This whole procedure would be made much easier if someone would just create a Modem Flashable Zip that overwrites the Modem files, but this method described below removes any risk of corrupted files as part of the flash.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This method also allows those folks that prefer to keep their device stock from messing around with the OS, which may prevent OTA updates from deploying to your device.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_prerequisites">Prerequisites</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You have already installed the android-tools package (<code>sudo yum install android-tools</code>) that provides the fastboot protocol and the Android Debug Bridge (ADB). On Linux, ADB "just works".</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you&#8217;re using Windows to do this:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>swap out forward-slashes for back-slashes</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>configure ADB on your Windows PC before continuing.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Look on XDA for great tutorials on installing and configuring ADB.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_download_the_recovery_image">Download the Recovery Image</h3>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
The commands from this point on are for fedora 21 (but should work fine with most flavours of Linux),
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Download the Update 2.0 factory images from the <a href="https://developer.nvidia.com/gameworksdownload#?search=SHIELD%20Tablet%20LTE&amp;tx=$additional,shield">NVidia Developer Page</a>. You need to become a registered developer to download these files directly, but if you do a search on XDA Forums you should find plenty of download mirrors.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you chose the factory images, extract the file to a working directory and change the .sh script permissions to executable.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Run <code>./extract-nv-recovery-image-shield-tablet-wx_un_do-<em>[version]</em>.sh</code> and wait for about 10 seconds for the licence agreement to display.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Scroll down to accept the T&amp;Cs and then type <strong>I ACCEPT</strong> to extract the required files to the working directory.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_unlock_bootloader_and_flash_recovery">Unlock Bootloader and Flash Recovery</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You are ready to flash the recovery image to the device. But make sure you are happy all files have been backed up: this is your last chance before your tablet is completely wiped.</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Connect the Shield Tablet to the PC.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Reboot to the bootloader using one of the following methods:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Software Method:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Run <code>adb reboot bootloader</code>.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>Hardware Method</p>
<div class="olist loweralpha">
<ol class="loweralpha" type="a">
<li>
<p>Press "Volume Down" &#8594; "Power" until you see the screen backlight flash,</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Keep holding "Volume Down" and release Power button until the device
boots.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you have not already unlocked the bootloader, run <code>sudo fastboot oem unlock</code>. This erases all user data, but you&#8217;re going to be doing that with the factory image flash process, so it is inconsequential.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Run <code>sudo ./flash-all.sh</code> and walk away. The recovery screen will not show any progress, but the terminal will: all is well if the HDD light is blinking away madly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Once the terminal returns to the command prompt, the tablet is ready to restart:</p>
<div class="olist loweralpha">
<ol class="loweralpha" type="a">
<li>
<p>Press the Vol Down key to select Reboot.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Press Power to restart the tablet and begin the first run process.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_post_update_boot_time_relax">Post-update Boot Time: Relax!</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You&#8217;ll remember that the first time this runs, it takes a very long time. The tablet will sit at the NVidia Logo screen for what seems like an eternity, and you may be concerned that you&#8217;ve bricked the tablet. Don&#8217;t be: patience is a virtue here. It will boot, and the world won&#8217;t end.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_install_an_ota_to_get_the_modem_files">Install an OTA to get the Modem Files</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I found out that after installing everything, I still couldn&#8217;t use my Virgin Mobile SIM to connect to the local network here. A bit of digging on XDA revealed a frustrating fact: the factory images don&#8217;t ship modem stacks! Why, I ask. WHY?</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The way folks recommended working around this issue is to wait for your tablet to detect that it has an older OS installed. This is why you download the 2.0 (Android 5.0.0) factory image, so you could receive the 2.1 (Android 5.0.1) OTA, and let it update to the latest version. The Modem stack included in the OTA should install and then you can begin using 4G data.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_you_did_it">You Did It!</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Great Job!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You&#8217;ve successfully factory reset your Shield Tablet to the Rest of World variant of the firmware. But here&#8217;s the problem: the stock firmware does not contain any modem updates. You need to install an OTA update to hopefully get the modem stack updated.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/01/15/Turning-a-Shield-Tablet-US-Version-into-a-Rest-of-World-Version.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/01/15/Turning-a-Shield-Tablet-US-Version-into-a-Rest-of-World-Version.html</guid><category><![CDATA[NVidia]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Shield Tablet]]></category><category><![CDATA[ US to Rest of World]]></category><category><![CDATA[ wx_na_wf to wx-un-do]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Poetic Revolution Case for the NVidia Shield Tablet (All Variants)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;ve been waiting for Poetic to release a good protection solution for the NVidia Shield Tablet, and they have done a pretty good job with the Poetic Revolution case. There are some small issues with the case, but overall it is definitely the most rugged case offering I&#8217;ve seen on the market at the time of writing.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/Poetic/Install_Complete.jpg" alt="Install Complete.jpg" width="300, height=" height="500"">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 1. Case in Portrait Mode</div>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/Poetic/Install_Complete_Landscape.jpg" alt="Install Complete Landscape.jpg" width="300, height=" height="500"">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 2. Case in Landscape Mode</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The case is sturdy in design, and definitely offers advanced protection for drops and mishaps. I really wish Poetic decided to adopt the style of the Slimline case range for the Nexus 7 2013. I&#8217;ll go into comparison detail in the Cons section.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_pros">Pros</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>It has an inner core of plastic that the device is pushed into. The outer layer is dense, semi-rigid plastic.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Built-in kick stand in landscape orientation.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The hard plastic insert has padding that elevates the tablet away from the case for airflow.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Even with bulky cable plugs, there seems to be plenty of room for HDMI cable connections, which was an issue with some other case designs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The screen edges have a nice bevel on them that lets you access the Android Nav buttons easily.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_cons">Cons</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>The dust cover flap for the sockets does not return to the stowed position easily after an extended period of being forced open.</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Slimline range had much softer rubber which made for much more flexible port covers.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I&#8217;m contemplating whether to just cut the flap off as it make it harder to access the ports anyhow. Once you cut, you can&#8217;t go back though…</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>The kick stand only works in Landscape orientation. In contrast, the Slimline range had the most versatile built-in stand that worked in multiple positions and orientations.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The buttons are difficult to press, and hard to blind-feel in the dark:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Slimline had protruding buttons, which are really great for feeling your way without looking.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_photos">Photos</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Here are some shots of the case, taken while I was installing it.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/Poetic/Case_Front.jpg" alt="Case Front.jpg" width="300, height=" height="500"">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 3. Front of the case immediately after unboxing.</div>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/Poetic/Case-Back.jpg" alt="Case Back.jpg" width="300, height=" height="500"">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 4. The back of the case, showing the kick stand.</div>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/Poetic/Shell_Internal.jpg" alt="Shell Internal.jpg" width="300, height=" height="500"">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 5. The right portrait side of the case, showing the button zone.</div>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/Poetic/Inner_and_Outer.jpg" alt="Inner and Outer.jpg" width="300, height=" height="500"">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 6. The internal plastic shell and the outer soft plastic.</div>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/Poetic/Connecter_Cutout_Insert.jpg" alt="Connecter Cutout Insert.jpg" width="300, height=" height="500"">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 7. The cutouts for the USB, HDMI, and Headphone plugs, and the left bass port.</div>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredleonmorgan.net/images/Poetic/Left_Side_Insert.jpg" alt="Left Side Insert.jpg" width="300, height=" height="500"">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 8. The plastic insert showing the portholes for the connectors.</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>What do you think about cases? Worth it? Or just bulky additions to your device?</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/01/14/Poetic-Revolution-Case-for-the-NVidia-Shield-Tablet-All-Variants.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/01/14/Poetic-Revolution-Case-for-the-NVidia-Shield-Tablet-All-Variants.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Poetic]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Revolution]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Tablet Cases]]></category><category><![CDATA[ NVidia Shield]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Down the Rabbit Hole With Mr Whippy]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>An ice cream van decided to roll down our street today, playing some undecipherable tune that wasn&#8217;t Greensleeves. This started me down an interesting internet trip about the history of Mr Whippy and Mobile Ice Cream vans in Australia.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I learned that Mr Whippy was introduced into Australia in 1962 after its incredible success in the UK in 1959. A fleet of custom built Commer Karrier vans&#8212;&#8203;fitted with the now synonymous Greensleeves chime box&#8212;&#8203;were shipped out from Southampton in the UK to begin operating in Sydney first, and subsequently all major regions of Australia. The vans were individually numbered as part of the franchise operation.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://mrwhippyherveybay.com/images/Mr.Whippys-at-Myers-2.gif" alt="Image of the first Mr Whippy Vans in Australia">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The history behind the music Ice Cream Vans played was the main reason why I started to search for information. It turns out that each country has different tunes they play. In Australia and New Zealand, it&#8217;s Greensleeves. This is largely because the song is in the Public Domain now and is royalty free. From what I&#8217;ve read on the history, it seems that some of the proliferation of this tune is due to the chime boxes on the imported trucks back in the 1960s, and the way this tune became almost synonymous with the Ice Cream Van in this country. Parents know it, and pass the knowledge down to their kids, who pass it to their kids. This is why over 50 years later, the song still resonates with me as 35 year old Ice Cream lover.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Until recently, one of the 11 tunes generally associated with Ice Cream Trucks in the USA was the tune <em>"Turkey in the Straw"</em>. The racist lyrics that were unfortunately attached to this tune are no longer considered acceptable to the public, and other tunes as diverse as the <em>"Super Mario Bros theme"</em> and <em>"The Entertainer"</em> are used to bring the kids to the curb.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ice_cream_van#In_Australia_and_New_Zealand">Wikipedia</a> is great if you want to learn about the history of Ice Cream vans worldwide, and the tunes they play. You can really go down the internet rabbit hole if you read the history of each song, so click if you dare…</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://mrwhippyherveybay.com/History.html">Mr Whippy Hervey Bay&#8217;s</a> History page is a great place to learn more about how Mr Whippy started in Australia and how the legacy is perpetuated by the Staff family of Hervey Bay, Queensland. It&#8217;s great to see that their original vans still use the original (yes, the 1960&#8217;s original) Italian Carpigiani ice cream machinery. That would be no mean feat to keep working. The Staff family even contributed to the book by Steve Tillyer entitled <strong>The Mr. Whippy Story</strong>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the 60&#8217;s I&#8217;d imagine Mr Whippy vans would be the only way you would have been able to enjoy a <em>Rocket</em>, <em>Sherbet</em>, <em>Hundreds and Thousands</em>, or <em>Choc Top</em>. These days, Soft Serve is available wherever you see a fast food burger chain. But it&#8217;s just not the same as walking up to the window and getting a cone covered with stuff, or having to quickly dart across the hot bitumen, and reach up to get the prize of a cool cone from a hole in a noisy truck.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So, what is your favourite Soft Serve variety?</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/01/11/Down-the-Rabbit-Hole-With-Mr-Whippy.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/01/11/Down-the-Rabbit-Hole-With-Mr-Whippy.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Ice_Cream]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Mr_Whippy]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Greensleeves]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Ice_Cream_Truck]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stern Modernises SAM to SPIKE]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_new_pinball_controller_for_a_new_era_of_pinball">New Pinball Controller for a New Era of Pinball</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;m very excited to learn that Stern Pinball has modernized their SAM pinball controller with a new system named SPIKE. The new system was announced along-side Stern&#8217;s latest pinball offering <strong>Wrestlemania</strong>. I&#8217;m not going to discuss the theme or licence because it has alread been covered by many podcasts, and reminds me quite a bit of Data East&#8217;s <strong>WWF Royal Rumble</strong> (which I really love).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you&#8217;ve ever looked inside the backbox of a pinball machine, you&#8217;ll be familiar with the bundes of wire and huge driver boards filling up the space. Not to mention the meters and meters of wire under the playfield surface. Not so with SPIKE.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_what_is_spike">What is SPIKE?</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredmorgs.github.io/images/Stern_SAM_SPIKE.jpg" alt="Cabinet view of SAM and SPIKE with an inverted playfield.">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>SPIKE (no one knows what that acronym or initialism stands for yet) uses a distributed micro-controller system, where boards specific to a subset of the overall pinball game are placed close to the components they control.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredmorgs.github.io/images/WWE_Flipper_Area.jpg" alt="The micro-controller flipper driver board that comprise the SPIKE system.">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This means far less wiring. Which in turn means far less cost, and increased reliability.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://jaredmorgs.github.io/images/SPIKE_Mainboard.jpg" alt="The SPIKE System Mainboard.">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Mainboard uses Linux to power the primary system, and replacable eMMC flash memory to store the game code on the board rather than the older EPROM technology. There is also a new short-circuit prevention circuit, which will prevent operators from blowing up lamp matrics and switch matrics. The replaceable sub-boards will make any field repairs much simpler if they fail.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The player features include a headphone jack, proper three channel sound, LEDs in the backbox for variable backbox lighting control (reduced playfield glare in low-light situations), better flipper tech (more on this below) and future possibilities for network play with additional Wi-Fi modules.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_general_feedback_from_the_pinball_community">General Feedback from the Pinball Community</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="https://pinside.com/pinball/forum/topic/sterns-new-platform-titled-spike">The PinSide Forum</a> has some interesting perspectives on the new system:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Apparently the very coldly-received 2012 <a href="http://www.ipdb.org/machine.cgi?id=5861)">Transformers The Pin</a> from Stern was basically "SPIKE Beta". I have a new appreciation for it, but only for the fact it was a beta testing platform. ;)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>This technology was also on location test at Modern Pinball NYC it seems. The AC/CD "Let There Be Rock" LE seemed to contain the SPIKE system in the backbox, a PinSide poster revealed in the thread, backed up with pics.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Game code is on a Compact MMC.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Dual-wound flippers. With both a Wind and Hold circuit, Stern catches up with Bally/Williams, who used this technology until they closed their pinball division in 2000.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The button battery on the main backbox board is mounted at right-angles to the board, which will prevent a common issue with electrolyte damage to board components from leaky batteries. Personally, I don&#8217;t know why they just didn&#8217;t go with an adapted Flash RAM board which you can retrofit onto older games.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Debate about the protocol: whether it is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CAN_bus">Controller Area Network</a> (CAN) or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RS-485">RS-485</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://pinside.com/pinball/forum/topic/sterns-new-platform-titled-spike/page/5#post-2159596">John_I</a> gives a great summary of the technology from an electronic engineer&#8217;s perspective.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>John_I confirmed the large driver board use good old "through hole" parts (that is, component with legs that go through holes in the PCB) rather than Surface Mount parts. This means that PinTechs can still fix boards rather than having to replace them. But, honestly, a good electronics engineer could do repairs to surface mount boards anyhow.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_pinsider_observations">PinSider Observations</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://pinside.com/pinball/forum/topic/sterns-new-platform-titled-spike/page/4#post-2158546">mcluvin</a> suggested networking could be made to email the operator for faults, and enable remote auditing. I personally think this will happen.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://pinside.com/pinball/forum/topic/sterns-new-platform-titled-spike/page/5#post-2158662">Pinchroma</a> expressed some concerns about entering WPA Wi-Fi keys, but I&#8217;d think this would be done with a keyboard through the USB port.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Very interesting times for Pinball, indeed.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>How long has it been since <strong>you</strong> played a game of Pinball?</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/01/08/Stern-Modernises-SAM-to-SPIKE.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/01/08/Stern-Modernises-SAM-to-SPIKE.html</guid><category><![CDATA[pinball]]></category><category><![CDATA[ SPIKE]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Stern]]></category><category><![CDATA[ MPU]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ways to Reduce Paper Reliance Through Technology]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I read a blog post about <a href="http://unclutterer.com/2010/11/30/identifying-bad-processes/">Identifying Bad
Processes</a> which suggested that:</p>
</div>
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>&#8230;&#8203;is your purse or wallet overflowing with receipts? Receipt clutter
is almost always caused by either not having a process for handling
receipts or having a process you don’t use because the method is
inconvenient, poorly designed, or not the best process for your
needs&#8230;&#8203;</p>
</div>
</blockquote>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It got me thinking about why we have so many receipts cluttering up our
wallets and purses.  Sure, there are some receipts that you simply must
keep for proof of purchase, or warranty purposes.  But then there are
those redundant receipts that vendors seem to give you (often without
asking if you actually <strong>want</strong> a receipt to start with).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For example, I used to always select "printed receipt" to see my bank
balance from an ATM. But as soon as I viewed the balance, I posted it
through the slot in the metal "Receipts" bin.  From the state of the overstuffed
receipts bin, I&#8217;d hazard a guess that most of us do the same. After
seeing the mess of receipts poking out of the bin, I made a conscious
decision to select "balance displayed on screen" instead.  One less
thing to put in the wallet.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Another thing that usually hangs around in my wallet is the humble
shopping list.  Not any more.  Those of us with smartphones have no
excuse for using paper lists anymore.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.keep">Google Keep</a>
now features a Share List option where you can collaborate on lists with other people: lists like your Shopping List. You can even run separate lists for different supermarkets or chain stores if you know an item can only be purchased from one shop. And when you pass the shop, you can choose whether Google Keep notifies you with a geo-fence notification. Tick off the items as you take them off the shelf and you won&#8217;t have to carry a pen with you either.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>How about when you need to collect an item that requires a reference
number?  Put it in your phone as a Google Keep item, or just in the notepad on
your device.  No need to use a sticky note that is only going to become
wedged in your wallet or purse and stick to stuff.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A quick twitter poll uncovered a number of other excellent solutions to
reduce your wallet bloat:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Buying lunch with EFTPOS; you aren&#8217;t going to return your sandwich,
so you don&#8217;t need a receipt.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Buying fuel from the petrol station; the fuel is in your car, you
can&#8217;t return it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Printing out online movie tickets; just make a calendar appointment
in your phone for the movie time and date, and put the reference
number in the appointment as well.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Receipts for Taxation purposes; in Australia, the ATO only requires
a bank statement for taxation <a href="http://law.ato.gov.au/atolaw/view.htm?docid=PSR/PS20057/NAT/ATO/00001">proof of purchase</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Receipts for warranty purposes: scan them and digitally file them in DropBox, Copy, or Google Drive. I guarantee they will be easier to find digitally than rifling through a paper-based system. And they won&#8217;t fade!</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>What other ways have you found to reduce your wallet bloat?</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/01/07/Ways-to-Reduce-Paper-Reliance-Through-Technology.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/01/07/Ways-to-Reduce-Paper-Reliance-Through-Technology.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Environment]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Process]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Android]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Google Keep]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Modular Christmas Light Idea That Is Begging To Be Made]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>During a Christmas long past, I had the most unpleasant job of untangling a 300 string set of these Christmas Lights. Being the smart geek, I had wound them around a large postage tube to try and keep them from getting untangled, but even that didn&#8217;t help.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>To cut a long story short, after a lot of violent shaking, and spaghetti maze solving, I untangled the string.
After hanging the damn things, half of the string just did not work. At all. What a soul destroying waste of time. Never again.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>We did purchase an LED set of lights, but it was a 100 string. We really needed a 300 string. My better half just would not put them up on the tree, saying they would look ridiculous. They probably would have. So, being the geek that I am, I got thinking about the problem and have come up with a Christmas Lights product that makes all the terrible design elements of Christmas Lights a thing of Christmas Past.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_the_pitch">The Pitch</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_overview">Overview</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Modular Christmas Lights, with the following features:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Green (or white), flat, flexible, cable.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Colour switching LEDs so you do not have to have one colour per strand.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Each light string is 1m long, and has keyed connectors.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>20 individual LEDs per strand (a bulb every 5 cm): this would give excellent light output.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_lengths">Lengths</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Usable in 100, 150, 200, 250, or 300 bulb lengths:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Connect how ever many you need.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Never have the problem with trying to wrap the excess bulb length around the bottom of the tree.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>LED bulb is mounted in a neat, terminal block style housing.</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>One light in center of cable, but connected internally to the correct cable will look a lot better than a LED that is protruding from the cable.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>No protruding bulbs means no tangle.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_bulb_control_module">Bulb Control Module</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Bulb Controller, with the following features:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Seven modes, similar to what most offer now.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Music Response mode. Responds to bass frequencies to control the light pulse.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Each mode cycles through with a single push button (like most on market now).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>LED 'mode' indicator built in, so you know exactly what mode is running.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>No bulky wall plug: normal corded wall plug, with unit sitting on the floor.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Auto detects the modular length connected based on pre-set resistance, and adjusts light intensity accordingly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Set the light intensity: soft or bright.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_packages_available">Packages Available:</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>300 bulb length, for big trees.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>150 bulb length for small trees.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Other lengths sold separately, for an affordable price.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>150 bulb length pack controller can be expanded up to 300 bulbs with separately purchased lengths.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_pack_includes">Pack Includes:</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Selected bulb length.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Bulb Controller.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Soft bag for lineal storage of string lengths, and all accessories.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So who wants to put up some venture capital and we get these puppies onto the market for Christmas next year?</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_update">Update</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I can&#8217;t believe that no one has made this a reality yet. What is wrong with you people? It almost makes me want to start a kickstarter and get these produced.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/01/07/A-Modular-Christmas-Light-Idea-That-Is-Begging-To-Be-Made.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2015/01/07/A-Modular-Christmas-Light-Idea-That-Is-Begging-To-Be-Made.html</guid><category><![CDATA[LED]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Christmas]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Comparing Shipito to Hop Shop Go]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I recently decided to take the plunge and purchase some products from Amazon.com that were only available in the US, and would not be shipped to anywhere other than USA addresses.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Because I live on the prisoner island, the great southern land known as Australia, I had little choice but to use a freight forwarder to get the product on-shipped to Aussie.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Because I&#8217;m impatient, I went with the first recommendation of <a href="http://shipito.com">http://shipito.com/</a>. If I had my time again, I probably would have opted for <a href="http://hopshopgo.com">http://hopshopgo.com/</a>.</p>
</div>
<table class="tableblock frame-all grid-all spread">
<caption class="title">Table 1. Feature Comparison</caption>
<colgroup>
<col style="width: 33.3333%;">
<col style="width: 33.3333%;">
<col style="width: 33.3334%;">
</colgroup>
<thead>
<tr>
<th class="tableblock halign-left valign-top">Feature</th>
<th class="tableblock halign-left valign-top">Shipito</th>
<th class="tableblock halign-left valign-top">Hop Shop Go</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Tax Free Eligibility (Oregon Address)</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Yes, but you need to pay for it: $10/month or $50/year.</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Free. The default address.</p></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Account verification process</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">This is a bit of a trip: scan/photograph documents; upload through the customer portal; wait for them to be verified (pretty quickly, to their credit).</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Nothing to do, providing you are already a verified PayPal customer.</p></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">User Interface</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Customer portal is a little dated and clunky, but functional once you work out how to use it.</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Customer Portal has a clear and easy to understand workflow. The information you need is all in the breadcrumb navigation, and cascades from the breadcrumb nav when you need it. It’s a BPM workflow, so you can easily relate the question or action back to a common workflow.</p></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Shipping payments/top up</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Handled through PayPal, or through your verified credit card. This can add a short amount of time to being able to use the service if you don’t have PayPal, or you are waiting to verify the small amount debited to your credit card. The small amount value was a bit of a pain for me, but this is the fault of my credit card provider, not Shipito.</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Integrated with your PayPal account. Uses your default funding source to pay for shipping.</p></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Customer Service</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Really fast, and efficient. I had an issue with my Credit Card verification process, and after a quick chat to an online customer service rep (during Aussie hours) I had the issue resolved.</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Can’t comment yet. Have not had to contact them. The website is very comprehensive, so I doubt I will ever need to contact them with a question.</p></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Shipping Costs</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Many options available. The cheapest is about $22, and if you want insurance for loss <strong>and</strong> damage, you must pay $1 to have the item photographed. All up with fees (random bank fees and a bit of courier mark-up), my first consignment was $32. I like to be able to know exactly what I’m up for clearly, so I can work out whether the vendor’s shipping is cheaper than the forwarder’s shipping. In this case I had no choice because the item wasn’t shipping to Australia.</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Flat rate, clearly described on the page (uses a number of providers at the back-end, but flat rate applies to all). Makes it easy to calculate what you might be up for. Additional package consolidation charges are declared up-front which helps you work out whether to hold or ship.</p></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Package Consolidation</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Free service lets you only store one package in your mailbox, therefore no consolidation option unless you opt for the $10/month option ($50/year if you are a regular user). I wasn’t really aware of this when signing up, so when Amazon shipped my part order, I had no choice but to get it shipped for A$32.</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Free service lets you store up to three packages for 30 days. After this time, a holding fee applies. I could have saved about $32 in shipping if I had used this service. Buyer’s remorse for sure.</p></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Discounts and Rebates</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Offers a coupon shopping service with discounts available for certain retailers. Get the code, enter it into the portal. Get the discount.</p></td>
<td class="tableblock halign-left valign-top"><p class="tableblock">Offers a third-party cash-back service that you sign up to. Order through their portal, and you get credit attributed to your PayPal account.</p></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_update">Update</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I managed to change the freight forwarding provider from shipito to Hop Shop Go, and I have to say the experience was fantastic! I know that Australia Post has also entered the market with a Portland-based freight forwarding service which from what I read is very much like Hop Shop Go. The freight charges appear to be about the same. It&#8217;s worth checking out in a market that is finally realising that there is no such thing as Geo Boundaries with purchasing any more.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2014/08/07/Comparing-Shipito-to-Hop-Shop-Go.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2014/08/07/Comparing-Shipito-to-Hop-Shop-Go.html</guid><category><![CDATA[freight forwarding]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Amazon.com]]></category><category><![CDATA[ USA to Australia]]></category><category><![CDATA[ shipito]]></category><category><![CDATA[ hop shop go]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google Play Music: From On-device to In The Cloud]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_updated_info">Updated Info</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Before Android, I was restricted to purchasing mobile devices with external memory slots or 32GB internal drives so I could manually transfer as much of my extensive music collection onto my primary listening device.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Back in 2013, I decided to put my faith in Google and I now use Google Music exclusively to manage my music collection, and have my music on any device when I want it.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Google&#8217;s Music service has fundamentally changed the way I consume! Over Christmas 2014, I was streaming purchased albums by <em>Pentatonix</em> to my HDTV through a Chromecast dongle from my Shield Tablet. I never dreamt back in 2012 that this would be possible, but here we are.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;m leaving the original post largely intact for posterity, however there are some updates that make using the service even better now:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>On Chrome, you have a web agent that manages syncing "external music" to Google Music. Before it was an RPM (for fedora) and a .exe for Windows. This change greatly streamlines the process of uploading music.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>You&#8217;ll probably find when you go in and attempt to edit an album&#8217;s details that Google has already noticed an issue with the details and has suggested better artwork and album metadata for you.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you own a Chromecast, check the offers regularly for Google Play Music <strong>All Access</strong> for free trials of the unlimited music service. It&#8217;s worth checking out.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Oh, and <strong>if</strong> you own a Chromecast, you would almost certainly tried using your device as a remote control for your music. This is great for parties where you want your guests to control the playlist.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_original_blog">Original Blog</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>When Google Play Music was made available in Australia, I thought I should at least give the service a go based on the positive reviews I read about the service.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Uploading 20,000 songs to the service seemed like a good start for my collection, but until doing so I didn&#8217;t realise my <strong>entire</strong> music collection was only 7000 songs small. I quickly realised that the offering was not 20,000 <strong>MB</strong>, but 20,000 <strong>actual songs</strong> (even if they were 320kbs quality).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I began purchasing albums directly from Google Play and loved the convenience of the albums being added to my library and available for playback instantly. And that&#8217;s on all devices sharing the same Google Account.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If I purchased an album outside the Play Store on a service such as BandCamp, I can dump the album into the watched folder on any PC and it is available on all my devices in less than 10 minutes (or less time if my upload speed is fast).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you are on the fence about the Google Play Music service, or cloud music services in general, these use-cases may encourage you to jump down from the pickets and into the cloud music pasture. These use-cases are a few I could think of based on problems I&#8217;ve directly experienced, or solutions to problems I&#8217;ve heard about from other people.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_use_case_1_wired_for_sound_wirelessly">Use Case 1 - Wired for sound, wirelessly.</h3>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_scenario">Scenario</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Over the weekend, I had to rebuild the Windows PC. I wanted to use my tablet for entertainment while I hand-held the upgrade process, but also wanted to have access to music while doing this boring task. I didn&#8217;t want to be wired to the speaker system with my tablet, as the headphone jack wasn&#8217;t long enough to reach the couch.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_solution">Solution</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Plug your mobile phone into the speaker system and launch the Play Music app on that device. Sit back on the couch and enjoy G+, and Pinball Arcade from the comfort of the couch on the tablet.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Or if you own a Chromecast, just stream your music from your tablet directly to the TV, and browse social media at the same time. Welcome to the future!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_use_case_2_where_there_s_a_computer_there_s_your_music">Use Case 2 - Where there&#8217;s a computer, there&#8217;s your music</h3>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_scenario_2">Scenario</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;m sitting in a public space that doesn&#8217;t have a Wi-Fi access point, or good GSM Data coverage and forgot to <strong>pin music</strong> (download for off-line play) to my device from Google Music. There&#8217;s a PC that has internet access and a speaker system attached in the public space.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_solution_2">Solution</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Log into the PC using your Google account. Boom! Instant
access to your entire music library. Start enjoying music over the PC
speakers instantly.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_use_case_3_physical_media_is_so_2005">Use Case 3 - Physical media is so 2005</h3>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_scenario_3">Scenario</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I want a new CD album, but never get a chance to go to a music store and
search through racks of CDs. And then I get the CD home and immediately
chuck it in a storage crate after converting it to MP3s. What a waste of
space.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_solution_3">Solution</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Purchase your music directly from Google Play, and it is available instantly across all your devices. No CD rack required. If you are a little concerned about Google holding your "only copy" of the album, then fear not because you can download an album up to two times from the service (so you can add it to your physical storage at home).</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_use_case_4_keeping_up_with_artist_releases_and_finding_similar_artists">Use Case 4 - Keeping up with artist releases, and finding similar artists.</h3>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_scenario_4">Scenario</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I want to keep up-to-date with my favourite artists but don&#8217;t have the time to rummage through CD bins at my local music store.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_solution_4">Solution</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A quick search of your favourite artist reveals all the albums they have for sale on Play Music, including the albums you have purchased or uploaded. You can instantly see gaps in your collection, and fill them instantly with an online album purchase. Legally. And with the preview track feature on the albums, you can always have a listen to the track to see if more recent albums by your favourite artist haven&#8217;t gone all avant-garde and hipster and no longer interest you.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you use Google Plus, you can also listen to albums in full when your G+ contacts share an album purchase in their stream. This is an interesting way of exposing yourself to new music.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2014/01/12/Google-Play-Music-From-On-device-to-In-The-Cloud.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2014/01/12/Google-Play-Music-From-On-device-to-In-The-Cloud.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Google Play Music]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Use Case]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Android]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Record Screen Demos on Fedora Using the Command Line (ffmpeg)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="toc" class="toc">
<div id="toctitle">Table of Contents</div>
<ul class="sectlevel1">
<li><a href="#_background">Background</a></li>
<li><a href="#_usage_example">Usage Example</a>
<ul class="sectlevel2">
<li><a href="#_what_does_all_that_mean">What does all that mean?</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#_alias_command">Alias Command</a></li>
<li><a href="#_procedure">Procedure</a>
<ul class="sectlevel2">
<li><a href="#_prerequisites">Prerequisites</a></li>
<li><a href="#_set_default_monitor">Set Default Monitor</a></li>
<li><a href="#_get_packages">Get Packages</a></li>
<li><a href="#_build_the_command">Build the Command</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#_summary">Summary</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_background">Background</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The ffmpeg command is broken down into the following primary parts:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>input</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>output (encode)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>output container (filename).</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>To record your desktop, you require two input sources to be configured:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Audio from your laptop mic, USB headset, or 3.5mm microphone/headset jack.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Video from the desktop of your computer.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_usage_example">Usage Example</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Rather than doing what we always do, and blindly copy pasta a command and run it, read the Build the Command section to understand the ffmpeg commands you see. You&#8217;ll start to learn that while this tool seems complicated, the commands are there for a reason, and in the order they are on purpose.</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code>ffmpeg -video_size 1920x1080 -framerate 30 -f x11grab -i :0.0+0,0 -f alsa -i plughw:1,0 -acodec libmp3lame -ar 48000 -ab 320k -vcodec libx264 Desktop_Recording.mp4</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>To stop the recording, press <code>Ctrl+C</code> in the terminal.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_what_does_all_that_mean">What does all that mean?</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This captures the left screen at 1920x1080 resolution, and uses the USB
Headset connected to the PC. The framerate is 30 fps. The audio is
encoded in MP3 format at 48000 khz @ 320kbps. The file saved is
<code>Desktop_Recording.mp4</code>, and is saved in the same directory you executed
this command in.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_alias_command">Alias Command</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Add the following alias to your <code>~/.bashrc</code> file, and you have a way of
easily recording from the command line with pre-set settings. All you
need to do is specify the target file name as <strong>[filename]</strong>.mp4, after
typing the command.</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code>alias Record_Desktop="ffmpeg -video_size 1920x1080 -framerate 30 -f x11grab -i :0.0+0,0 -f alsa -ac 1 -i plughw:1,0 -acodec libmp3lame -ar 48000 -ab 320k - codec libx264 "</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
The space is important at the end of the alias. It lets you specify a file name after the alias.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_procedure">Procedure</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_prerequisites">Prerequisites</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you just try and run the command above for the first time, I can almost guarantee that you&#8217;ll get errors. There are some things you need to do before you can begin constructing the command to suit your Fedora installation.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_set_default_monitor">Set Default Monitor</h3>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Open gnome-display-properties in Gnome 3 (Activities &gt; Displays)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Drag the screen you want to capture to the left of the dialog.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Click the left monitor in the dialog.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Write down the resolution displayed. This is required in the command line procedure.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Ensure the black title bar is dragged over to the screen you want to capture.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This sets the record target display as 0.0, or DEFAULT.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_get_packages">Get Packages</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Install Codecs from RPM Fusion Non-free repo:</p>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
The required package names seem to change periodically, particularly between major releases of Fedora. If you notice package name changes, let me know and I&#8217;ll update the package names.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Install the rpmfusion-nonfree repo</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><code>sudo yum install ffmpeg lame lame-devel</code></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>Install Codecs from RPM Fusion Free repo\</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><code>sudo yum install h264enc x264 x264-devel</code></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_build_the_command">Build the Command</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The following sections explain the ffmpeg command. If you have come to this blog post and some of the parameters are out of date, you should at least be able to work out the basic required structure. If you do notice any issues, send me an email or leave a comment and I&#8217;ll incorporate your feedback.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_input">Input</h4>
<div class="sect4">
<h5 id="_audio_input_parameters">Audio Input Parameters</h5>
<div class="dlist">
<dl>
<dt class="hdlist1">-f alsa</dt>
<dd>
<p>Specify an input format of ALSA audio.</p>
</dd>
<dt class="hdlist1">-i plughw:[card],[device]</dt>
<dd>
<p>	Specify the card and device number of the microphone you want to record
from. If you are using a USB headset or mic, do the following to correctly set this parameter:</p>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Plug in the device and run one of the following commands:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><code># cat /proc/asound/cards</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code># arecord -l</code></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>You will get a listing of available sound cards.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Change <code>plughw:0,0</code>, to <code>plughw:[n],0</code>, where [n] corresponds to the device ID of the headset or mic you want to use.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</dd>
</dl>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect4">
<h5 id="_video_input_parameters">Video Input Parameters</h5>
<div class="dlist">
<dl>
<dt class="hdlist1">-f x11grab</dt>
<dd>
<p>Specifies an input format of X11 Screen Capture.</p>
</dd>
</dl>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock warning">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-warning" title="Warning"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
The <code>-videosize</code> and <code>-framerate</code> parameters <strong>must</strong> appear first in the command. You are passing the frame rate and screen resolution <strong>to</strong> the display and capture area. Place it after <code>-i</code> and you are specifying these values for the <strong>next</strong> input format.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="dlist">
<dl>
<dt class="hdlist1">-video_size 1920x1080</dt>
<dd>
<p>Specifies the screen’s resolution. Alter this to the current display resolution of your device as reported in the Prerequisites.</p>
</dd>
</dl>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock important">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-important" title="Important"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
There are <strong>no spaces</strong> in the video_size values.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="dlist">
<dl>
<dt class="hdlist1">-framerate 30</dt>
<dd>
<p>Specify a frame rate of 30 fps. This setting does produce large file sizes, but the visual quality is perfect.</p>
</dd>
<dt class="hdlist1">-i :0.0+0,0</dt>
<dd>
<p>The setting as written captures the left screen. (0.0 specifies the $DEFAULT (system default) monitor display.
   The second set of numbers after the <code>+</code> specifies the offset value from the left-hand display. For example, if you want to capture the second screen, and the L/H monitor runs 1920x1080, the offset value is <code>-i :0.0+1920,0</code>).</p>
</dd>
</dl>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_output">Output</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>ffmpeg output properties are set using codecs and their specific
settings. You need settings for both Audio and Video. Specify the Output (encode) properties in the order you specified the input types:</p>
</div>
<div class="sect4">
<h5 id="_audio_output_parameters">Audio Output Parameters</h5>
<div class="dlist">
<dl>
<dt class="hdlist1">-acodec libmp3lame</dt>
<dd>
<p>Specifies that you will encode using mp3 libraries. These libraries encode fine when pushed to services such as Vimeo.</p>
</dd>
<dt class="hdlist1">-ar 48000</dt>
<dd>
<p>Specifies the audio frequency is 48000 khz. This frequency is "CD Quality".</p>
</dd>
<dt class="hdlist1">-ab 320k</dt>
<dd>
<p>Specifies the audio bitrate is 320kbps. This is the highest you can go with MP3 audio.</p>
</dd>
</dl>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect4">
<h5 id="_video_output_parameters">Video Output Parameters</h5>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The only parameter you need to provide is the following one.</p>
</div>
<div class="dlist">
<dl>
<dt class="hdlist1">-vcodec libx264</dt>
<dd>
<p>Specifies the h.264 codec, otherwise known as MP4 video.</p>
</dd>
</dl>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_output_container">Output Container</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Finally, the output file name, which is added as the last command line argument. Ensure it has the .mp4 container extension in the name.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_summary">Summary</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Because you read the full blog post, you now know what all those parameters mean, and can go tell someone else about how to use ffmpeg. Nice one!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2014/01/11/Record-Screen-Demos-on-Fedora-Using-the-Command-Line-ffmpeg.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2014/01/11/Record-Screen-Demos-on-Fedora-Using-the-Command-Line-ffmpeg.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Screencast]]></category><category><![CDATA[ ffmpeg]]></category><category><![CDATA[ fedora]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Making a Standing Desk using a Shelving Rail System]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_summary">Summary</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You can make a standing desk out of shelving rails and brackets, and some MDF board. It really doesn&#8217;t have to be expensive or difficult. I built mine for about \$150, but that cost also included paint, and some tools I didn&#8217;t have. See Basic Costs and Ancilliary Costs for further details.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_lessons_learned">Lessons Learned</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Measure twice, corroborate your measurements, drill once.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The internet can show you how to correctly mount shelves.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Read procedures, even if you think you know how to erect shelving.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Don&#8217;t be too proud to get all the facts before proceeding.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Wall studs are your friend.</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Measure these first. Your studs will determine how wide your shelves can be in some scenarios.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Don&#8217;t even think about using heavy-duty plasterboard screws for this task. They really aren&#8217;t strong enough.</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>This shelving is holding all your precious IT gear, not your collection of Lego models.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Studs or nothing.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>Don&#8217;t cheap out on tools:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Get what you need and don&#8217;t compromise.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Beg, borrow, (but don&#8217;t steal - because stealing is bad m&#8217;kay).</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>Get your wood cut at your local big hardware shop. They usually do it for free, and unless you have a circular saw and a keen eye, you will get much better results having it done on a cutting station.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_basic_costs">Basic Costs</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Double-slot Upright Shelving Rail White 100cm x 2 = $14.50</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Double-slot Bracket 320mm White x 6 = $29.40</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Brackets of this size should have holes in the bottom to screw through. Ensure yours do.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>MDF Standard 16mm 900 x 600mm Sheet x 2 = $18.00</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>One of these boards gets cut in half, so you get two 300mm shelves.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>Box of 50 10g 50mm Wood Screws (you only need 8) = $9.90</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Basic costs total <strong>$79.00</strong> if you have the following Anciliary items:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Stud detector</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Decent spirit level, at least 60cm long</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Some undercoat and gloss paint</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Sample pot paint roller.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Nuts, bolts, and screws that can go through the shelf brackets to anchor the shelves into place.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_ancillary_costs">Ancillary Costs</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>60cm Aluminium Spirit Level - $15.00</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>300g Hole Filler (hopefully <strong>you</strong> won&#8217;t need this) - $4.50</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Zinsser Bullseye 1-2-3 Primer Sealer Undercoat 1 litre (you only need about 500mls) - $21.90</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Really, any cheap undercoat will do. This brand was the smallest and cheapest at the time.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>1L Pascal Trim W/based Gloss White Enamel (hard-wearing for desks) - $27.95</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Any Enamel Gloss paint will be great.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Gloss is easy to clean, and won&#8217;t be susceptible to greasy finger marks.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>Sample Pot Paint Roller with extra roller - $2.00 (seriously worth it).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Drill, with a selection of drill bits</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>I had one of these.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
Borrow any tools in the ancillary list to save a chunk of change on the raw build cost.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Total for all these ancillaries total about <strong>$72.00</strong></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_vital_statistics">Vital Statistics</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Shelving rails are spaced 450mm apart:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>For me, this was the distance between studs (the vertical strips of timber that hold a plasterboard wall in place).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>You will need to measure your stud distance before continuing. Don&#8217;t stuff this up, otherwise that Hole Filler on the Ancillaries list will be in your hardware cart.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>Shelves are 900mm long.</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>This was the closest pre-cut MDF sheet I could find at Masters North Lakes.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you want to convert your standing desk back to a seated desk, ensure you put the bottom of the shelving rails at a height that is equal to your current seated desk. You can see that in my picture.</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>I used thin nuts and bolts to secure the shelf bracket to the MDF.</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>You can use wood screws if you like for the 300mm shelves, drilled from underneath the shelf through the bracket holes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I didn&#8217;t want to risk it for the 600mm shelf:</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>It can be subjected to some load if you lean on the table.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>There is 300mm of overhang resting on the shelf brackets.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Bolts will ensure it doesn&#8217;t go anywhere.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_what_about_the_old_desk">What About The Old Desk?</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The original desk can be used for any number of things:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Put your drinks on there and keep them away from your IT gear.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Put admin stuff like filing trays, game figures, your collection of Start Wars Lego.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Use the original desk as a break desk when having a phone or video call.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_update_jan_2015">UPDATE Jan 2015</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I have transitioned to a standing desk environment so well now that the original desk is now used as a workbench in the garage for times when I need to fix the odd toy or household item.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_complimentary_benefits">Complimentary Benefits</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Because I&#8217;m a tight arse, and didn&#8217;t have enough money to purchase some tools, the cool people where I worked loaned me most tools I needed.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I took this one step further, and made a forum where staff can record what tools they are willing to loan to other staff members. So far, it seems to have had a slow response, but as time goes by I can see it as a great way to have an unofficial tool co-op for everyone to benefit from.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Could your office use a Tool Co-Op?</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2013/04/23/Making-a-Standing-Desk-using-a-Shelving-Rail-System.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2013/04/23/Making-a-Standing-Desk-using-a-Shelving-Rail-System.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Cheap and Cheerful]]></category><category><![CDATA[ DIY]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Tool Co-op]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Standing Desk]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Shelving]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Masters North Lakes]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Do Not Pull The Battery From A Running Galaxy S2]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_background">Background</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For other phone manufacturers, pulling the battery from a running device does nothing except turn the device
off. Not so with Android, or at least in my case the Samsung Galaxy S2
International Version.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_cause">Cause</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I needed to get the Serial Number under the battery compartment, so decided to pull the battery on my Samsung Galaxy S2 handset without shutting down correctly.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_consequence">Consequence</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>When I rebooted, I got a stack of Force Close messages cascading on each other. The messages entered into a continuous loop so I couldn&#8217;t access any phone functions.
Forums suggested that the only way to correct the issue was to factory reset the handset, which is no good if you haven&#8217;t done a back-up recently.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_fix">Fix</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I found a method that allowed me to get the phone working again, without having to fully factory reset the device and lose personal data as a result.</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>If you can, power off your device correctly using the power button and let it fully shut down.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Take the battery out and leave it out for 15 seconds to remove any residual charge in the mainboard.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Replace the battery (no need to put the battery cover back on).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Press and hold <strong>Home Key</strong> + <strong>Volume Up</strong> + <strong>Power Button</strong>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Keep holding these buttons until you see a green Android robot symbol. During this process, the white and black Samsung screen should display, turn off, then display again.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Once the Android robot symbol disappears, the SGS2 Data Recovery Screen displays (which looks a bit like a command prompt on Linux machines).
<strong>Release all buttons</strong>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>At the top of the screen, are four menu options (in green on my model).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Highlight <strong>Reboot Phone</strong> using the Volume Rocker.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Press the Home Key to select the option.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Let the phone reboot.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Give the handset time to attempt to load all data from the external microSD, and the internal storage.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_result">Result</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>You should see no Force Close messages, and your phone should boot as it
did before you pulled the battery.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you do see Force Close messages, the Force Close messages should be
so few that you can note the com.android. classnames that are causing
the Force Close message. Uninstall the app that is causing the Force
Close issue (in my case it was the Facebook for Android app), then
reinstall it. You should be back to normal.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2012/03/07/Do-Not-Pull-The-Battery-From-A-Running-Galaxy-S2.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2012/03/07/Do-Not-Pull-The-Battery-From-A-Running-Galaxy-S2.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Pull Battery]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Infinite Loop Force Close]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Force Close Message on Boot]]></category><category><![CDATA[ SGS2]]></category><category><![CDATA[ SGSII]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Android]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Using Open Source to Reinvigorate Pinball 2000]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I remember when I was restoring pinball machines that I learned a very important lesson about computer repair. I accidentally caused mainboard damage to a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pinball_2000">Pinball 2000</a> (Pin2K) game: <a href="http://www.ipdb.org/search.pl?any=star+wars&amp;search=Search+Database&amp;searchtype=quick#4458">Star Wars: Episode 1</a>.  It is very easy to do, because the two Molex connectors from the ATX power supply were not <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electrical_connector#Keying">keyed</a>, and you could reverse the ground for power. I did this, and took out the power circuit on the mainboard.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This was a <strong>big</strong> problem, because the Pin2K mainboards were a BAT-style PC mainboard (running a Cyrix Media GX CPU which was connected to a Cyrix CX5520 bridge). These motherboards were used mainly in set-top boxes such as cable TV systems. The Pin2K series used a PCI custom card called a PRISM card. This card contained all the game logic, sound effects, and video packages for the games. If the power spike travelled to the PRISM card, you basically had yourself a fantastic $8000 piece of furniture.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>At the time, the machine was mothballed.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I discovered that <a href="http://www.bigguyspinball.com/index.shtml">Big Guys Pinball</a> have reverse engineered the Pin2K core, and created some custom boards which can be used to replace damaged Pin2K logic box systems. The new system is called <strong>nucore</strong>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The great thing is they are using Linux (Ubuntu), and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commercial_off-the-shelf">COTS</a> motherboards and Video Cards, to make this system a reality. You can purchase the components separately, or as a plug-and-play system ready for production use.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Hooray for Open Source, and Ingenuity!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>Update</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Unfortunately the Big Guys at Big Guys Pinball ran into a little bit of strife in 2014 during the pinball resurgence. I believe they were kindly asked to discontinue producing these boards because <a href="http://www.planetarypinball.com/mm5/merchant.mvc?">Planetary Pinball</a> had the exclusive rights to reproduce all Bally and Williams parts (including, unfortunately, the Pin2K hardware system). To date, I am not aware of any efforts to resume production. This is a real shame, and unless Planetary Pinball get their act together, it may see the end of crippled Pin2K units.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2011/10/04/Using-Open-Source-to-Reinvigorate-Pinball-2000.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2011/10/04/Using-Open-Source-to-Reinvigorate-Pinball-2000.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Pinball 2000]]></category><category><![CDATA[ nucore]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Open Source]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Linux]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Big Guys Pinball]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Pin2K]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ways to Reduce Paper Reliance Through Technology]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I read a blog post about <a href="http://unclutterer.com/2010/11/30/identifying-bad-processes/">Identifying Bad
Processes</a> which suggested that:</p>
</div>
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
&#8230;&#8203;is your purse or wallet overflowing with receipts? Receipt clutter
is almost always caused by either not having a process for handling
receipts or having a process you don’t use because the method is
inconvenient, poorly designed, or not the best process for your
needs&#8230;&#8203;
</blockquote>
<div class="attribution">
&#8212; unclutterer.com
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It got me thinking about why we have so many receipts cluttering up our
wallets and purses.  Sure, there are some receipts that you simply must
keep for proof of purchase, or warranty purposes.  But then there are
those redundant receipts that vendors seem to give you (often without
asking if you actually <strong>want</strong> a receipt to start with).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For example, I used to always select "printed receipt" to see my bank
balance from an ATM. But as soon as I viewed the balance, I posted it
through the slot in the metal "Receipts" bin.  From the state of the overstuffed
receipts bin, I&#8217;d hazard a guess that most of us do the same. After
seeing the mess of receipts poking out of the bin, I made a conscious
decision to select "balance displayed on screen" instead.  One less
thing to put in the wallet.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Another thing that usually hangs around in my wallet is the humble
shopping list.  Not any more.  Those of us with smartphones have no
excuse for using paper lists anymore.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.keep">Google Keep</a>
now features a Share List option where you can collaborate on lists with other people: lists like your Shopping List. You can even run separate lists for different supermarkets or chain stores if you know an item can only be purchased from one shop. And when you pass the shop, you can choose whether Google Keep notifies you with a geo-fence notification. Tick off the items as you take them off the shelf and you won&#8217;t have to carry a pen with you either.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>How about when you need to collect an item that requires a reference
number?  Put it in your phone as a Google Keep item, or just in the notepad on
your device.  No need to use a sticky note that is only going to become
wedged in your wallet or purse and stick to stuff.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A quick twitter poll uncovered a number of other excellent solutions to
reduce your wallet bloat:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Buying lunch with EFTPOS; you aren&#8217;t going to return your sandwich,
so you don&#8217;t need a receipt.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Buying fuel from the petrol station; the fuel is in your car, you
can&#8217;t return it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Printing out online movie tickets; just make a calendar appointment
in your phone for the movie time and date, and put the reference
number in the appointment as well.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Receipts for Taxation purposes; in Australia, the ATO only requires
a bank statement for taxation <a href="http://law.ato.gov.au/atolaw/view.htm?docid=PSR/PS20057/NAT/ATO/00001">proof of purchase</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Receipts for warranty purposes: scan them and digitally file them in DropBox, Copy, or Google Drive. I guarantee they will be easier to find digitally than rifling through a paper-based system. And they won&#8217;t fade!</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>What other ways have you found to reduce your wallet bloat?</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2010/12/04/Ways-to-Reduce-Paper-Reliance-Through-Technology.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://jaredleonmorgan.net/2010/12/04/Ways-to-Reduce-Paper-Reliance-Through-Technology.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Environment]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Process]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Android]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Google Keep]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Morgan]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>